原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译    IronDerby   老冰棍Eunice
等一下  先别放
Okay, hold on, don't shoot.
看准目标了吗
You see where you're going?
翻译     斯嘉丽意难平还我卡特  凉开水要沸腾哭我铁人
那好
Okay.
想想要如何射中目标
Now, let's worry about how you get there.
翻译     C·A   24_1900   终局之草
脚往外挪一点
Gotta move your foot here.
脚尖对准这边
Point your toe this way.
胯向这边转
Your hips here.
校对    复仇草
好吗
Okay?
-能看到吗  -能
- Can you see? - Yeah.
确定吗
Are you sure?
时间轴    查查陪基神一起逃离漫威宇宙   Avis
-现在呢  还能看到吗  -看不到
-How about now? Can you see now?  - No.
那现在呢
How about now?
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的wholock   大葱跟妮妮告别
好
All right.
准备好了吗  三根手指
Ready? Three fingers.
漂亮
Nice!
后期    8T
投得好  孩子
Nice throw, kiddo.
球来了
Here you go.
总监    草草
你们要蛋黄酱还是芥末酱
Hey, you guys want mayo? Or mustard?
还是都要
Or both?
谁在热狗上放蛋黄酱
Who puts mayo on a hot dog?
也许你两个弟弟会
Probably your brothers.
两份芥末酱  谢谢  孩儿他妈
Uh, two mustard, please! Thanks, Mama.
好的
Got it!
内特  蛋黄酱还是芥末酱
Nate, mayo or mustard?
番茄酱行吗
How about ketchup?
番茄酱  番茄酱我也有
Or ketchup. I got ketchup, too.
注意手肘
Mind your elbow.
射得好  鹰眼
Good job, hawk-eye.
去拿箭吧
Go get your arrow.
你们俩
Hey, guys!
别练了  汤好了
Enough practice. Soup's on!
好的
All right.
我们来了  饿死了
We're coming. We're hungry.
莱拉  我们走
Lila, let's go.
莱拉
Lila?
亲爱的
Honey?
Hey, babe?
亲爱的
Babe?
孩子们
Boys!
劳拉
Laura!
你不用这样的
You don't need to do that.
因为你只需要保持这个姿势
Because, uh, you're just holding the position.
对
Oh, yeah.
差点就中了
That was close.
进门  我们现在各得一分
That's a goal. We are now one apiece.
我想再试一次
I would like to try again.
我们平手  紧张吗
We're tied up. Feel the tension?
好玩吧
It's fun.
射得太差了  现在你有机会赢了
That was terrible. Now you have a chance to win.
你赢了
And you've won.
恭喜
Congratulations.
比赛公平
Fair game.
玩得不错
Good sport.
开心吗
You have fun?
挺开心的
It was fun.
这东西在录吗
This thing on?
波茨小姐  小派
Hey, Miss Potts. Pep.
如果你发现了这段录像
If you find this recording...
别发到社交网络上
don't post it on social media.
不然肯定要哭死一群
It's gonna be a real tearjerker.
我不知道你是否会看到
I don't know if you're ever gonna see these.
我都不知道你是否还...
I don't even know if you're still...
天呐  但愿你还在
Oh, God, I hope so.
今天是第21天
Today's day 21.
不  第22天
No, uh, 22.
如果不是因为凝视真正的虚无空间
You know, if it wasn't for the existential terror...
而产生的存在恐惧
of staring into the literal void of space,
我会说我今天感觉好一点了
I'd say I'm feeling a little better today.
感染已经结束了
Infection's run its course,
这要谢谢那位蓝恶魔
thanks to the Blue Meanie back there.
你一定会很喜欢她的
Oh, you'd love her.
非常务实
Very practical.
就是有点虐待倾向
Only a tiny bit sadistic.
燃料电池在打斗中被损坏
So, the fuel cells were cracked during battle...
我们找到了办法逆转离子电荷
and we figured out a way to reverse the ion charge...
争取到了大约48小时的飞行时间
and bought ourselves about 48 hours of flight time.
但是现在已经彻底不能用了
But it's now dead in the water.
距最近的便利店有上千光年
Thousand light years from the nearest 7-Eleven.
明天早上氧气将会耗尽
Oxygen will run out tomorrow morning...
然后就完了
and that'll be it.
小派  我知道我说过再不制造意外了
Pep, I know I said no more surprises...
但我得说  我真的希望能完成这最后一个
but I gotta say I was really hoping to pull off one last one.
但是现在看来...
But it looks like...
你知道看起来如何
Well, you know what it looks like.
别为此而难过
Don't feel bad about this.
其实  如果你痛心难过个几周
I mean, actually, if you grovel for a couple weeks...
然后带着巨大的罪恶感继续生活下去...
and then move on with enormous guilt...
也许我应该躺会儿
I should probably lie down for a minute.
让眼睛休息一下
Go rest my eyes.
请知道
Please know...
当我渐渐睡去  会和近来的每晚一样
when I drift off, it'll be like every night lately.
我很好  真的很好
I'm fine. Totally fine.
我会梦到你
I dream about you.
因为一直都是你
Because it's always you.
没能阻止他
Couldn't stop him.
我也一样
Neither could I.
等等
Hang on.
我没救下那孩子
I lost the kid.
托尼  我们都输了
Tony, we lost.
派珀她...
Is, uh...?
-太好了  -天呐
- Oh, good. - Oh, my God!
天呐
Oh, my God!
没事了
It's okay.
距灭霸来到地球  已经过了23天
It's been 23 days since Thanos came to Earth.
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
詹姆斯·巴恩斯
艾瑞克·塞尔维格
山姆·威尔逊
世界各国政府分崩离析
World governments are in pieces.
霍普·凡·戴恩
旺达·马克西莫夫
仍在运转的部门
The parts that are still working...
亨利·皮姆
斯科特·朗
在进行人口普查  看来他是成功了
...are trying to take a census and it looks like he did...
彼得·帕克
苏睿
他做到了他声称要做的事
He did exactly what he said he was gonna do.
特查拉
灭霸消灭了...
Thanos wiped out...
尼克·弗瑞
一半的生命
...50% of all living creatures.
他现在在哪
Where is he now? Where?
我们不知道
We don't know.
他开了个传送门  穿过去了
He just opened a portal and walked through.
他是哪根筋不对
What's wrong with him?
他很愤怒
Oh, he's pissed.
他觉得自己失败了
He thinks he failed.
没错  他是失败了
Which, of course, he did...
但我们都失败了  不是吗
but you know, there's a lot of that going around, ain't there?
说真的  要不是你开口说话
Honestly, until this exact second
我还以为你是小熊玩偶
I thought you were a Build-A-Bear.
没准我就是
Maybe I am.
我们已经找了灭霸三周
We've been hunting Thanos for three weeks now.
扫描外太空
Deep space scans...
卫星搜索  然而毫无发现
and satellites, and we got nothing.
托尼  你和他交手过
Tony, you fought him.
谁跟你说的
Who told you that?
我没跟他"交手"
I didn't fight him.
他用一颗星球暴揍了我
No, he wiped my face with a planet...
然后那个布里克街魔术师把宝石交出去了
while the Bleecker Street magician gave away the store.
实情就是这样  根本谈不上交手
That's what happened. There was no fight,
-好吧  -他根本不可战胜
- Ok.  - 'cause he's not beatable.
他有没有透露过任何线索或坐标
Did he give you any clues, any coordinates, anything?
我几年前就预料到了
I saw this coming a few years back.
我看到了幻象  我本来不想相信
I had a vision. I didn't wanna believe it.
以为自己是做梦
Thought I was dreaming.
托尼  我需要你集中精神
Tony, I'm gonna need you to focus.
我曾经也需要你
And I needed you.
我是指过去
As in, past tense.
那比你现在的需求重要  太迟了  哥们
That trumps what you need. It's too late, buddy.
抱歉
Sorry.
知道我需要什么吗  我需要刮胡子
You know what I need? I need a shave.
而且我记得我告诉过你们所有人
And I believe I remember telling all youse...
托尼  托尼
Tony, Tony!
还在和不在的  我们需要的
...alive and otherwise, that what we needed
是一套保护世界的战衣
was a suit of armor around the world.
记得吗
Remember that?
不管那是否会影响到我们宝贵的自由
Whether it impacted our precious freedoms or not.
那才是我们曾需要的
That's what we needed.
但那并没成功  不是吗
Well, that didn't work out, did it?
我说过我们会输的
I said we'd lose.
而你说  "那就一起输"
You said, "We'll do that together, too."
你猜怎么着  队长
And guess what, Cap?
我们输了
We lost.
而你不在场
And you weren't there.
不过我们就是干这个的  不是吗
But that's what we do, right?
总是在事后行动  我们是"复仇者"
Our best work after the fact? We're the "Avengers."
"复仇者"  而不是"预防者"
We're the "Avengers," Not the "Pre-vengers."
-好了  -对吗
- Okay. - Right?
-你说得很明白了  先坐下吧  -好
- You made your point. Just sit down, okay? - Okay.
-不  我还没说完  -托尼
- No, no, here's my point. You know what? - Tony,
-对了  她可真棒  -你身体不好  坐下
- She's great by the way. - you're sick. Sit down.
我们需要你  你是新生力量
We need you. You're new blood.
一群身心疲惫的老家伙
Bunch of tired old mules.
我没什么可给你的  队长
I got nothing for you, Cap.
没坐标
I got no coordinates...
没线索  没战略  没选择
no clues, no strategies, no options.
屁都没有
Zero. Zip. Nada.
也没有信任  骗子
No trust, liar.
给你  拿着
Here, take this.
你找到他  戴上它
You find him, you put that on...
躲起来
you hide.
-托尼  -我没事
- Tony! - I'm fine.
让我...
Let me...
布鲁斯给他注射了镇静剂
Bruce gave him a sedative.
估计他今天之内都不会醒了
He's gonna probably be out for the rest of the day.
你们照顾好他
You guys take care of him...
我回来时给他捎点克佐利亚的神药
and I'll bring him a Xorrian elixir when I come back.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去杀灭霸
To kill Thanos.
我们通常一起行动
You know, we usually work as a team here and, uh,
私下里说一句  现在士气有点低落
between you and I, morale's a little fragile.
我们知道太空是你的领域
We realize up there is more your territory,
但这也是我们的战斗
but this is our fight, too.
你知道他在哪吗
You even know where he is?
我认识可能知道的人
I know people who might.
不必麻烦了
Don't bother.
我可以告诉你灭霸在哪
I can tell you where Thanos is.
灭霸花了很长时间来完善我
Thanos spent a long time trying to perfect me.
他改造我时  总爱说他的伟大计划
And when he worked, he talked about his Great Plan.
就算被拆解了  我仍然想讨好他
Even disassembled, I wanted to please him.
我会问
I'd ask...
等计划完成后  我们去哪
where would we go once his plan was complete?
他每次的回答都一样
And his answer was always the same.
"去花园"
"To the Garden."
真有爱  灭霸还有退休计划
That's cute. Thanos has a retirement plan.
那他在哪
So, where is he?
灭霸打响指时
When Thanos snapped his fingers...
地球成了宇宙级能量涌的
Earth became ground zero for a power surge
爆发点
of ridiculously cosmic proportions.
可谓前无古人
No one's ever seen anything like it.
直到两天前...
Until two days ago...
这个星球上又发生了一次
on this planet.
灭霸在那儿
Thanos is there.
他又用了一次宝石
He used the stones again.
我们去的话  人手不足
We'd be going in shorthanded, you know?
宝石还在他手里  所以...
Look, he's still got the stones, so...
那我们就去夺回来
So, let's get 'em.
用宝石把大家救回来
Use them to bring everyone back.
就这样
Just like that?
对  就这样
Yeah. Just like that.
哪怕有一丝挽回一切的希望
Even if there's a small chance that we can undo this...
我们也必须为不在这里的每个人一试
I mean, we owe it to everyone who's not in this room to try.
就算我们去  我们怎么知道
If we do this, how do we know
结局会跟上次不一样
it's gonna end any differently than it did before?
因为上次你们没有我
Because before you didn't have me.
新来的妹子
Hey, new girl?
这里每个人都是干超级英雄的
Everybody in this room is about that superhero life.
要是你不介意我问问
And if you don't mind my asking,
这么久以来你都去哪了
where the hell have you been all this time?
宇宙里还有很多星球
There are a lot of other planets in the universe.
可惜那些地方没有你们
And unfortunately, they didn't have you guys.
我喜欢她
I like this one.
我们去干掉那个王八蛋
Let's go get this son of a bitch.
复仇者联盟4：终局之战
好了
Okay.
这里谁没上过太空
Who here hasn't been to space?
怎么了
Why?
你们最好别吐在我飞船里
You better not throw up on my ship.
接近跳跃点  三
Approaching jump in three...
二  一
two, one.
我下去侦查
I'll head down for recon.
这次会成功的  史蒂夫
This is gonna work, Steve.
我知道
I know it will.
因为如果不成功  我不知道该怎么办
'Cause I don't know what I'm gonna do if it doesn't.
没有卫星  没有战舰  没有军队
No satellites. No ships. No armies.
没有任何地面防御
No ground defenses of any kind.
只有他
It's just him.
那就够了
And that's enough.
不
Oh, no.
宝石在哪
Where are they?
回答问题
Answer the question.
宇宙需要修正
The universe required correction.
之后  宝石就没有用了
After that, the stones served no purpose...
只是诱惑
beyond temptation.
你杀了数万亿生灵
You murdered trillions!
你应该感激
You should be grateful.
宝石在哪
Where are the stones?
没了
Gone.
化成原子了
Reduced to atoms.
你两天前还用过的
You used them two days ago!
我用宝石摧毁了宝石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
差点要了我的命
It nearly killed me.
但大业已成
But the work is done.
注定会完成的
It always will be.
我是宿命
I am inevitable.
我们得把这里翻个底朝天  他肯定在撒谎
We have to tear this place apart. He has to be lying!
我父亲有很多特点
My father is many things.
但他不撒谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你  女儿
Thank you, daughter.
也许我过去对你太残酷了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
什么
What?
你干了什么
What did you do?
我砍脑袋了
I went for the head.
五   年   后
那个...我...
So, I...
他们走了
我们该
何去何从
前两天去约会了
went on a date the other day.
这是五年来第一次
It's the first time in five years.
我坐在餐桌前
You know? I'm sitting there at dinner.
都不知道该谈些什么
I didn't even know what to talk about.
你们谈了什么
What did you talk about?
还是老一套  时过境迁了
Same old crap. You know, how things have changed.
我的工作  他的工作
My job, his job.
我们多想念纽约大都会队
How much we miss the Mets.
然后就陷入了沉默
And then things got quiet...
侍者上沙拉时  他哭了
then he cried as they were serving the salads.
那你呢
What about you?
我上甜点之前哭的
I cried just before dessert.
但我明天还要再见他  所以...
But I'm seeing him again tomorrow, so...
很棒
That's great.
你已经完成了最难的部分  你鼓起勇气行动了
You did the hardest part. You took the jump.
尽管你不知道结果会如何
You didn't know where you were gonna come down.
就是这样
And that's it.
我们得这样勇敢地迈出一个个小步
That's those little brave baby steps we gotta take...
努力再次让自己完整  寻找意义
to try and become whole again, try and find purpose.
我1945年落入冰层中
I went in the ice in '45,
那时我才刚遇见自己的一生挚爱
right after I met the love of my life.
再醒来已是七十年后
Woke up 70 years later.
人得向前看
You gotta move on.
必须向前看
Gotta move on.
世界在我们手中
The world is in our hands.
就交给我们了  各位
It's left to us, guys.
我们得做点什么
And we gotta do something with it.
不然...
Otherwise...
灭霸就等于杀了所有人
Thanos should've killed all of us.
旧金山
"随心寄"自助寄存
朗
什么鬼
What the hell?
霍普
Hope?
保安
救命
失踪
孩子
Kid!
Hey, kid!
这里发生什么了
What the hell happened here?
消失者
天呐
Oh, my God!
拜托
Oh, please!
Please, please!
不不不不
No, no, no. No.
不
No.
不好意思  抱歉
Excuse me. Sorry.
凯西  不
Oh, Cassie, no.
不不不
No, no, no.
不不
No, no.
千万不要有凯西
Please, please, please. No, Cassie.
斯科特·朗
什么
What?
凯西
Cassie?
爸
Dad?
你长大了好多
You're so big!
禁区  勿入
我们登上了那艘
Yeah. We boarded that
丹弗斯说十分可疑的战舰
highly-suspect warship Danvers pinged.
那是一艘有传染病的垃圾驳船
It was an infectious garbage scow.
谢谢你的可靠情报
So, thanks for the hot tip.
你们更近嘛
Well, you were closer.
现在我们全身都是垃圾味
Yeah. And now we smell like garbage.
你采集到震动读数了吗
You get a reading on those tremors?
是非洲板块下的轻微下冲
'Twas a mild subduction under the African plate.
能看到吗  要怎么处理
Do we have a visual? How are we handling it?
小娜
Nat.
只是海底地震
It's an earthquake under the ocean.
处理方式  就是不处理
We handle it by not handling it.
卡罗尔  下个月你会回来吗
Carol, are we seeing you here next month?
不太可能
Not likely.
怎么  你要再去剪一次头发吗
What? You gonna get another haircut?
听着  毛脸
Listen, fur face.
我要负责的地域很广
I'm covering a lot of territory.
发生在地球上的这些事
The things that are happening on Earth
到处都在发生
are happening everywhere.
在成千上万个星球上
On thousands of planets.
好吧  说得也是
All right, all right. That's a good point.
说得也是
That's a good point.
所以你们可能很长一段时间见不到我了
So, you might not see me for a long time.
好吧  那...
All right. Uh, well...
这个频道会一直开启
This channel's always active.
所以如果发生任何事
So, if anything goes sideways...
任何人在不该惹麻烦的地方制造麻烦
anyone's making trouble where they shouldn't...
都先通知我
comes through me.
-好  -好
- Okay.  - Okay.
那好
All right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你在哪
Where are you?
墨西哥
Mexico.
联邦调查局发现了一房间的尸体
The Federales found a room full of bodies.
似乎是一群贩毒集团的人
Looks like a bunch of cartel guys...
甚至都没机会掏枪
never even had a chance to get their guns off.
八成是敌对帮派干的
I mean, it's probably a rival gang.
但不是
Except it isn't.
肯定是巴顿
It's definitely Barton.
他在这里做的事
What he's done here...
他过去几年里做的事
what he's been doing for the last few years...
他所留下的场面
I mean, the scene that he left...
我得说
I gotta tell you,
我心里都有点不想找到他
there's a part of me that doesn't even wanna find him.
你能查出他接下来要去哪吗
Will you find out where he's going next?
小娜
Nat?
拜托了
Please?
好
Okay.
我倒想提出亲自给你下厨
You know, I'd offer to cook you dinner, but...
但你似乎已经很痛苦了
you seem pretty miserable already.
你是来洗衣服的吗
You here to do your laundry?
也来看看朋友
And to see a friend.
显然  你的朋友很好
Clearly, your friend is fine.
我过桥的时候
You know, I saw a pod of whales
看到了一群鲸鱼
when I was coming over the bridge.
在哈德逊河里吗
In the Hudson?
船只少了  水就清了
There's fewer ships... cleaner water.
如果你要跟我说
You know, if you're about to tell me
去看好的一面
to look on the bright side...
我就用花生酱三明治砸你的头
I'm about to hit you in the head with a peanut butter sandwich.
抱歉
Sorry.
旧习难改
Force of habit.
我一直告诉大家要放下过去
You know, I keep telling everybody they should move on...
继续生活
and grow.
有些人这么做了
Some do.
但是我们不行
But not us.
如果我放下过去  谁来做这些事
If I move on, who does this?
也许这些事不需要做
Maybe it doesn't need to be done.
以前我一无所有
I used to have nothing.
然后我拥有了这些
And then I got this.
这份工作
This job.
这个家庭
This family.
我因此
And I was
变得更好
I was better because of it.
虽然他们都不在了
And even though they're gone...
我还是在尽量变得更好
I'm still trying to be better.
我觉得我们俩都需要有点私生活
I think we both need to get a life.
你先来
You first.
有人在吗
Is anyone home?
我是斯科特·朗
This is, uh, Scott Lang.
我们几年前在机场见过
We met a few years ago at the airport...
德国的机场
in Germany?
我是那个变大的人  我当时戴了面具
I was the guy that got really big. I had a mask on.
-你们大概认不出我  -这是以前的信息吗
- You wouldn't recognize me. - Is this an old message?
蚁人  我知道你们知道我
Ant-Man? I know you know... I know you know that.
-那是前门  -我真的需要和你们谈谈
- It's the front gate.  - I really need to talk to you guys.
斯科特
Scott.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah.
你们俩学过量子物理学吗
Have either of you guys ever studied quantum physics?
只有一点点了解
Only to make conversation.
好吧  是这样...
All right, so...
五年前  就在...
five years ago, right before...
灭霸的事发生前...
Thanos...
我进入了一个叫量子域的地方
I was in a place called the quantum realm.
量子域有它自己的微观宇宙
The quantum realm is like its own microscopic universe.
要想进去  你得变得非常非常小
To get in there, you have to be incredibly small.
霍普  她是我的...
Hope. She's my, um...
她本是我的...
She was my...
她本应该把我拉出来的
She was supposed to pull me out.
然后灭霸的事发生了...
And then Thanos happened...
我就被困在里面了
and I got stuck in there.
很遗憾  这五年一定很漫长
I'm sorry, that must have been a very long five years.
是啊  问题就在这里
Yeah, but that's just it.
并不漫长
It wasn't.
对我来说  只有五个小时
For me, it was five hours.
量子域的法则
See, the rules of the quantum realm
跟这个世界不一样
aren't like they are up here.
一切都不可预测
Everything is unpredictable.
那个三明治有人要吗
Is that anybody's sandwich?
我饿死了
I'm starving.
斯科特
Scott.
你说的是什么意思
What are you talking about?
所以...
So...
我想说的是...
what I'm saying is...
在量子域里  时间有不同的运行方式
time works differently in the quantum realm.
唯一的问题是  现在
The only problem is right now
我们没法在其中定位
we don't have a way to navigate it.
但如果有办法呢
But what if we did?
我一直在思考这个
I can't stop thinking about it.
如果我们能想办法控制这种混沌
What if we could somehow control the chaos...
并在其中定位呢
and we could navigate it?
如果我们有办法
What if there was a way...
在某个特定时间点
that we could enter the quantum realm
进入量子域
at a certain point in time...
然后在另一个特定时间点
but then exit the quantum realm
离开量子域呢
at another point in time?
比如说
Like...
-在灭霸打响指之前  -等等
- Like before Thanos. - Wait.
你指的是时间机器吗
Are you talking about a time machine?
不  不  当然不是  不是时间机器
No. No, of course not. No, not a time machine.
这更像是...
This is more like a...
没错  就是时间机器
Yeah. Like a time machine.
我知道  这很疯狂  非常疯狂
I know, it's crazy. It's crazy.
但我就一直在思考这个
But I can't stop thinking about it.
肯定有...
There's gotta be...
办法的...
some way...
-是很疯狂  -斯科特
- It's crazy. - Scott.
我能收到一只浣熊发的邮件
I get emails from a raccoon...
所以  再没什么算是"疯狂"了
so nothing sounds crazy anymore.
那么  我们要跟谁讨论这个
So, who do we talk to about this?
开饭咯
Chow time!
摩古娜
Maguna.
摩根·H·斯塔克  你想吃午饭吗
Morgan H. Stark, you want some lunch?
定义一下"午饭"  不然
Define "lunch" or be
-就等着被灭吧  -好吧
- disintegrated. - Okay.
你不应该戴这个  好吗
You should not be wearing that, okay?
这是我给妈妈做的周年纪念
That is part of a special anniversary gift
特别礼物里的
I'm making for Mom.
好了  想吃午饭吗
There you go. You thinking about lunch?
我可以拿莴苣包一把蟋蟀给你
I can give you a handful of crickets on a bed of lettuce.
-不  -你不是想吃那个吗
- No. - That's what you want.
你怎么找到这个的
How did you find this?
-在车库里  -真的吗
- Garage. - Really?
-你是有意去找它的吗  -没有
- Were you looking for it? - No.
反正我找到了
I found it, though.
你喜欢进车库是吗
You like going in the garage, huh?
爸爸也是
So does Daddy.
其实没关系  我给妈妈买的礼物她从来不穿
It's fine, actually. Mom never wears anything I buy her.
那么  我要...
So, I'm gonna...
不  我们知道这听上去多疯狂
No. We know what it sounds like.
托尼  在经历过这一切之后
Tony, after everything you've seen,
-难道还真有不可能的事吗  -量子波动
- is anything really impossible? - Quantum fluctuation
达到普朗克尺度
messes with the Planck scale...
大卫·德将量子理论与多重宇宙理论结合
提出回到过去只是进入另一个平行宇宙
并引出德氏观点
which then triggers the Deutsch Proposition.
我们能认同这一点吗
Can we agree on that?
谢谢
Thank you.
通俗地讲  就是你无法回到这里了
In layman's terms, it means you're not coming home.
-我回来了  -不对
- I did. - No.
你是碰巧幸存了
You accidentally survived.
这是十亿分之一的宇宙侥幸
It's a billion-to-one cosmic fluke.
现在你想进行...
And now you wanna pull a...
你怎么说的来着
What do you call it?
时间盗窃
A time heist?
没错  时间盗窃  当然了
Yeah, a time heist. Of course.
我们之前怎么没想到呢
Why didn't we think of this before?
因为这太好笑了  简直是白日梦
Because it's laughable. Because it's a pipe dream.
无限宝石都在过去
The stones are in the past.
我们可以回去拿到它们
We could go back, we could get them.
我们可以自己打响指  把所有人带回来
We can snap our own fingers. We can bring everybody back.
或者让事情变得更糟  对吗
Or screw it up worse than he already has, right?
我觉得我们不会的
I don't believe we would.
不得不说  有时我还挺怀念你的乐观
Gotta say it. I sometimes miss that giddy optimism.
然而  如果没有合理可行的方法
However, high hopes won't help
来安全地进行所谓的时间盗窃
if there's no logical, tangible way
寄予厚望也没用
for me to safely execute said time heist.
我认为最可能的后果
I believe the most likely outcome
就是我们共同灭亡
will be our collective demise.
只要我们严格遵守时间旅行的规则就不会
Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.
就是说  不可以跟过去的自己交谈
All right? It means no talking to our past selves...
不可以给体育比赛下注
no betting on sporting events.
我得让你打住了  斯科特
I'm gonna stop you right there, Scott.
你真要跟我说
Are you seriously telling me
你拯救宇宙的计划
that your plan to save the universe...
是基于《回到未来》的吗
is based on Back to the Future?
-是吗  -不是
- Is it? - No.
很好  你刚刚害我有点担忧
Good. You had me worried there.
因为那就扯淡了
'Cause that would be horseshit.
量子物理的原理不是那样的
That's not how quantum physics works.
托尼
Tony.
我们必须奋起抗争
We have to take a stand.
我们抗争了  但还是落得这个地步
We did stand. And yet, here we are.
我知道你有很多顾虑
I know you got a lot on the line.
你有妻子  女儿
You got a wife, a daughter.
但我也失去了对我非常重要的人
But I lost someone very important to me.
很多人都是
A lotta people did.
而现在  我们有机会让她回来
And now, now we have a chance to bring her back...
让所有人回来
to bring everyone back,
而你却告诉我  你甚至都不...
and you're telling me that you won't even...
是的  斯科特  我甚至都不
That's right, Scott. I won't even.
我做不到
I can't.
妈妈让我来救你
Mommy told me to come and save you.
干得好  你救下我了
Good job. I'm saved.
我真希望你们是来问我其他事的
I wish you were coming here to ask me something else.
什么都行
Anything else.
我真的很高兴见到你们  我只是...
I'm honestly happy to see you guys, I just...
对了  我们准备了六人份的午餐
Oh, look, the table's set for six.
托尼  我懂
Tony. I get it.
我为你高兴  真的
And I'm happy for you. I really am.
但这是我们的第二次机会
But this is a second chance.
我的第二次机会就在这儿呢  队长
I got my second chance right here, Cap.
我不能拿她冒险
Can't roll the dice on it.
只要不谈工作  你们可以留下来用午餐
If you don't talk shop, you can stay for lunch.
他害怕了
Well, he's scared.
他没有错
He's not wrong.
是啊  但是  我们该怎么办
Yeah, but, I mean, what are we, what are we, what are we gonna do?
我们需要他  我们就这么放弃吗
We need him. What, are we gonna stop?
不  我想把这事做好
No, I wanna do it right.
我们需要一个大大脑
We're gonna need a really big brain.
比他的还大吗
Bigger than his?
别这样  怎么好像就我一个人在吃
Come on, I feel like I'm the only one eating here.
尝尝那个
Try some of that.
来点炒蛋
Have some eggs.
我好困惑
I'm so confused.
现在就是令人困惑的年代
These are confusing times.
是啊  不  不  我不是那个意思
Right, no, no. That's not what I meant.
我懂啦  我开玩笑的
Nah, I get it. I'm kidding!
我知道  这很疯狂
I know, it's crazy.
我都开始穿衬衫了
I'm wearing shirts now.
是啊  什么  怎么会  为什么
Yeah. What? How? Why?
五年前  我们惨败
Five years ago, we got our asses beat.
只不过我更惨
Except it was worse for me...
因为我输了两次
'cause I lost twice.
先是绿巨人输了  后来班纳又输了
First, Hulk lost, then Banner lost...
再后来  我们都输了
and then, we all lost.
没人怪你  布鲁斯
No one blamed you, Bruce.
我怪
I did.
这么多年来  我一直把绿巨人
For years, I've been treating the Hulk
当成一种疾病
like he's some kind of disease...
一种需要摆脱的东西
something to get rid of.
但后来  我开始视他为出路
But then, I start looking at him as the cure.
我在伽马实验室待了18个月
Eighteen months in the gamma lab.
把思想和力量融为了一体
I put the brains and the brawn together...
现在看看我
and now, look at me.
两个自我的最佳状态
Best of both worlds.
-打扰一下  绿巨人先生  -什么事
- Excuse me, Mr. Hulk? - Yes.
我们能跟你合影吗
Can we get a photo?
当然可以  小朋友
100%, little person.
来  站过来  能帮个忙吗
Come on, step on up. Do you mind?
-当然  -谢谢
- Oh, yeah, yeah. - Thanks.
说"绿"
Say "Green."
-绿  -绿
- Green. - Green.
拍到了吗
Did you get that?
拍得很好
That's a good one.
你们也想跟我合个影吗  我是蚁人
Did you want to grab one with me? I'm Ant-Man.
他们是绿巨人的粉丝
They're Hulk fans.
-他们不知道蚁人  -等等  不  不
- They don't know Ant-Man. - Wait. No, no.
-他难过了  -没人知道
- He feel bad. - Nobody...nobody does.
-他想跟你们...  -我不想合影
- No, he wants you...  - I don't want a picture.
-他想跟你们合影  -陌生人很危险
- He wants you to take a picture with him. - Stranger danger.
你看  他都说不要了
Yeah, look, he's even saying no, he doesn't.
-我懂  我也不想  -别这样  那孩子
- I get it. I don't want it, either. - But come on, the kid, but...
-我不想跟他们合影  -可你...
- I don't want a picture with them. - But you...
-他会难过的  -抱歉
- He's gonna feel bad. - Sorry.
他们乐意的  他们说愿意了
They're happy to do it. They said they'll do it.
-我不想合影  -我们可以拍的
- I don't want to do it. - We can do it.
-不  你难过了  -把手机拿走
- No, you...you feel bad. - Take the goddamn phone.
好吧
Okay.
-谢谢你  绿巨人先生  -不用谢  孩子们
- Thank you, Mr. Hulk. - No, it was great, kids.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
绿巨人来了
Hulk out!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
Dab手势
Dab.
-布鲁斯  -要听妈妈的话
- Bruce. - Listen to your mom.
她最懂了
She knows better.
关于我们刚刚谈到的
About what we were saying.
好吧
Right.
时间旅行重来一次的事
The whole time travel do-over?
各位  这不是我专长的领域
Guys, it's outside of my area of expertise.
这事你都搞定了
Well, you pulled this off.
我记得这曾经也看似不可能
I remember a time when that seemed pretty impossible, too.
我有个小灵感
I've got a mild inspiration.
我想看看行不行得通
I'd like to see if it checks out.
所以  今晚收工前
So, I'd like to run one last sim
我想再做一次模拟
before we pack it in for the night.
这一次  以莫比乌斯环的形态
This time, in the shape of a Mobius strip,
请逆转
inverted, please.
正在处理
Processing.
好吧  把那个粒子的特征值
Right, give me the eigenvalue of that particle
进行光谱分解
factoring in spectral decomp.
-这会需要点时间  -请稍等
- That'll take a second. - Just a moment.
不成功也没事  我只是...
And don't worry if it doesn't pan out. I'm just kinda...
模型渲染完毕
Model rendered.
建模成功
该死
Shit!
你怎么起来了  小丫头
What are you doing up, little miss?
-该死  -不  我们不能说那种话
- Shit. - Nope. We don't say that.
只有妈妈可以说那个词
Only Mommy says that word.
那是她创造的  是她的专属词
She coined it. It belongs to her.
你怎么还不睡
Why are you up?
因为我还有大事要做
'Cause I've got some important shit going on here!
要不然呢
Why do you think?
不  我有心事
No, I got something on my mind.
我有心事
I got something on my mind.
是果汁冰棍吗
Was it juice pops?
是的
Sure was.
这是敲诈  敲诈是个词
That's extortion. That's a word.
你想要什么味的
What kind you want?
英雄所见略同
Great minds think alike.
果汁冰棍  正是
Juice pops exactly was on
我心里所想
my mind.
吃完了吗  不要了
You done? Yeah?
现在没了
Now you are.
来  擦擦嘴
Here. Wipe.
很好  躺下吧
Good. That face goes there.
给我讲个故事
Tell me a story.
讲故事
A story.
从前  摩古娜上床睡觉  讲完了
Once upon a time, Maguna went to bed. The end.
-这故事太糟糕了  -怎么了
- That is a horrible story. - Come on,
这是你最爱的故事
that's your favorite story.
超级爱你[爱你好多吨]
Love you tons.
我爱你三千
I love you 3,000.
三千  这数真大
3,000. That's crazy.
快睡觉  不然我把你玩具全卖了
Go to bed or I'll sell all your toys.
晚安
Night night.
虽然这不是竞争
Not that it's a competition...
但她爱我三千哦
but she loves me 3,000.
是吗
Does she, now?
你大概也就在六百到九百之间吧
You were somewhere in the low 6 to 900 range.
你在看什么
Whatcha reading?
关于堆肥的书
Just a book on composting.
堆肥有什么新门道
What's new with composting?
-有趣的科学...  -我想出来了
- Interesting science... - I figured it out.
顺便说一句
By the way.
我们是在聊同一件事吗
And, you know, just so we're talking about the same thing...
时间旅行
Time travel.
什么
What?
这...
That's...
太惊人了
amazing and
也很可怕
terrifying.
是啊
That's right.
我们真的很幸运
We got really lucky.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道
I know.
很多人可没这么幸运
A lot of people didn't.
对  我也不可能帮助所有人
Nope. And I can't help everybody.
看来你可以
Sorta seems like you can.
除非我停手
Not if I stop.
我可以马上收手不干
I can put a pin in it right now and stop.
托尼
Tony...
劝你收手
trying to get you to stop...
是我这辈子少数做不到的事之一
has been one of the few failures of my entire life.
我有几分觉得  我该把它
Something tells me I should put it in a
锁进盒子里  沉进湖底
lockbox and drop it to the bottom of the lake...
然后上床睡觉
and go to bed.
但你能安心睡着吗
But would you be able to rest?
好  准备好  时间旅行测试1
Okay, here we go. Time travel test number one.
斯科特  启动
Scott, fire up...the, uh,
车里那玩意
van thing.
断路器已安装好
Breakers are set.
紧急发电机已就绪
Emergency generators are on standby.
很好  因为如果我们烧断了电网
Good, because if we blow the grid,
我可不想把小不点丢在上世纪五十年代
I don't want to lose, uh, Tiny here in the 1950s.
-你说什么  -他在开玩笑呢
- Excuse me? - He's kidding.
你不能说这种话
You can't say things like that.
就是个冷笑话而已
It was a bad joke.
你是在开玩笑  对吧
You were kidding, right?
我不知道  这可是时间旅行
I have no idea. We're talking about time travel here.
要么就是玩笑  要么就是玩完
Either it's all a joke, or none of it is.
我们准备好了
We're good!
戴上你的头盔
Get your helmet on.
斯科特  我要把你送回一周之前
Scott, I'm gonna send you back a week...
让你待一个小时
let you walk around for an hour,
然后10秒后带你回来
then bring you back in 10 seconds.
懂吗
Make sense?
完全明白
Perfectly not confusing.
祝你好运  斯科特  你能行的
Good luck, Scott. You got this.
你说得对
You're right.
我能行的  美国队长
I do, Captain America.
三秒倒计时
On a count of three...
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
各位
Guys?
这感觉不对劲
This doesn't feel right.
怎么回事
What is this?
-这是怎么了  -那是谁
- What's going on? - Who is that?
-等等  -那是斯科特吗
- Hold on. - Is that Scott?
当然是了
Yes, it's Scott.
-怎么回事  布鲁斯  -我的背
- What's going on, Bruce? - Oh, my back!
-这又怎么回事  -等等的
- What is this? - Hold on a second.
-能让让吗  -当然
- Could I get a little space here? - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你能把他变回来吗
Can you bring him back?
我在努力呢
I'm working on it.
是个婴儿
It's a baby.
-是斯科特  -婴儿的斯科特
- It's Scott. - As a baby.
-他会长大的  -把斯科特变回来
- He'll grow. - Bring Scott back.
我说断电时  就断电
When I say kill the power, kill the power.
天呐
Oh, my God.
准备...断电
And... kill it!
有人尿在我裤子里了
Somebody peed my pants.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
但我不确定是婴儿的我  还是老年的我
But I don't know if it was baby me or old me.
还是就是我
Or just me me.
时间旅行啊
Time travel!
怎么了
What?
我觉得这绝对是成功啊
I see this as an absolute win.
干吗拉个脸
Why the long face?
我猜猜  他变成婴儿了
Let me guess, he turned into a baby.
还不止  对  你怎么来了
Among other things, yeah. What are you doing here?
是爱波罗悖论
It's the EPR Paradox.
你们没能让朗在时间里移动
Instead of pushing Lang through time,
而是让时间在朗身上流动了
you might've wound up pushing time through Lang.
这很不好弄  很危险
It's tricky, dangerous.
真该有人提醒你注意的
Somebody could have cautioned you against it.
你提醒了
You did.
是吗
Oh, did I?
幸好我来了
Well, thank God I'm here.
不管怎样  我解决了
Regardless, I fixed it.
完全好用的时间空间定位仪
A fully functioning time-space GPS.
我只想要和平
I just want peace.
原来怨恨会腐蚀心灵  我讨厌它
Turns out resentment is corrosive, and I hate it.
我也是
Me, too.
我们有机会拿到宝石
We got a shot at getting these stones,
但我得告诉你我最看重什么
but I gotta tell you my priorities.
找回我们失去的  希望可以
Bring back what we lost, I hope, yes.
留住我得到的  我必须  不惜一切
Keep what I found, I have to, at all costs.
或许  不用杀身成仁
And maybe not die trying.
那样最好了
Would be nice.
听上去不错
Sounds like a deal.
托尼  这好吗
Tony, I don't know.
怎么了
Why?
这是他为你造的
He made it for you.
而且  说实在的  我得赶紧从车库里取出来
Plus, honestly, I have to get it out of the garage
不然要被摩根拿去滑着玩了
before Morgan takes it sledding.
谢谢  托尼
Thank you, Tony.
你能别声张吗
Will you keep that a little quiet?
我可没给全队都带礼物来
Didn't bring one for the whole team.
是全队都来吧
We are getting the whole team, yeah?
我们正在集结人手呢
We're working on that right now.
人类
Hey, Humie.
大绿呢
Where's Big Green?
在厨房里吧
The kitchen, I think.
好赞啊
That's awesome.
罗德  降落时小心
Rhodey, careful on re-entry.
降落区有个白痴
There's an idiot in the landing zone.
天呐
Oh, God.
好啊  普通大小的哥们
What's up, Regular-Sized Man?
欢迎来到新阿斯加德  请慢速行驶
跟金宫殿  魔法锤比
Kind of a step down from the golden palaces
差远了啊
and the magic hammers and whatnot.
有点同情心嘛  伙计
Hey, have a little compassion, pal.
他们先失去了阿斯加德  然后又失去了半数人民
First, they lost Asgard, then half their people.
他们大概有个家就很开心了
They're probably just happy to have a home.
你们不该来的
You shouldn't have come.
女武神
Valkyrie!
见到你真高兴  生气姑娘
Great to see you, angry girl!
我觉得你另外两个形态哪个都比这样好
I think I liked you better either of the other ways.
这是火箭
This is Rocket.
你好
How ya doing?
他不会见你们的
He won't see you.
那么糟吗
It's that bad, huh?
我们每月只能见到他一次
We only see him once a month
在他来取"补给"时
when he comes in for "supplies."
啤酒
那么糟啊
It's that bad.
是啊
Yeah.
搞什么
What the...?
这里面一股腐臭
Something died in here!
有人吗  托尔
Hello? Thor!
你是来修电视的吗
Are you here about the cable?
电影频道两周前就收不到了
The Cinemax went out two weeks ago and...
体育频道也都模模糊糊的
the sports are all kinda fuzzy and whatnot.
托尔
Thor?
伙计们  天呐
Boys! Oh, my God!
天呐  见到你们太好了
Oh, my God, it's so good to see you!
过来  你这可爱的小坏蛋
Come here, cuddly little rascal.
别了  别介了
Yeah, no, I'm good. I'm good.
真没必要
That's not necessary.
绿巨人  你认识我的朋友米克和寇格吧
Hulk, you know my friends Miek and Korg, right?
-你们好  -你们好
- Hey, boys! - Hey, guys.
好久没见
Long time no see.
啤酒在桶里
Beer's in the bucket.
有无线网  自己登吧
Feel free to log on to the Wi-Fi.
没有密码的
No password, obviously.
托尔  他又来了
Thor, he's back.
电视上那小子刚刚又喊我蠢货了
That kid on the TV just called me a dickhead again.
新手大师
Noobmaster.
对  新手大师69
Yeah, NoobMaster69
-喊我蠢货  -我受够了
- called me a dickhead. - I am sick of this.
新手大师  还是托尔
Noobmaster, hey, it's Thor again.
雷神哦
You know, the God of Thunder.
听着  伙计  如果你不马上退出游戏
Listen, buddy, if you don't log off this game immediately,
我就飞去你家
I am gonna fly over to your house,
冲进你正躲在的地下室里
come down to that basement you're hiding in,
扯掉你的胳膊  塞进你屁眼里
rip off your arms, and shove them up your butt!
没错
Oh, that's right, yes!
去你爸那儿哭吧  小混蛋
Go cry to your father, you little weasel.
谢谢  托尔
Thank you, Thor.
他再敢欺负你就告诉我  好吗
Let me know if he bothers you again, okay?
非常感谢  我会的
Thank you very much. I will.
你们想喝点啥吗  我们喝什么
So, you guys want a drink? What are we drinking?
我有啤酒  龙舌兰  什么都有
I've got beer, tequila, all sorts of things.
伙计
Buddy.
-你没事吧  -嗯  我没事  怎么了
- You all right? - Yes, I'm fine. Why?
我看上去不好吗
Why, don't I look all right?
你看上去像融化的冰淇淋
You look like melted ice cream.
怎么  你就是来玩的吗
So, what's up? You just here for a hang, or what?
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
我们或许有机会修复一切
There might be a chance we could fix everything.
电视吗
What, like the cable?
因为这事折磨我几周了
'Cause that's been driving me bananas for weeks.
是灭霸
Like Thanos.
别提那个名字
Don't say that name.
是啊  我们这里不提那个名字的
Yeah, we don't actually say that name in here.
请把你的手拿开
Please take your hand off me.
我知道那...家伙
Now, I know that guy...
可能让你害怕
might scare you.
怎么会呢
Why would I be...?
我怎么会怕那家伙
Why would I be scared of that guy?
是我杀了那家伙  记得吗
I'm the one who killed that guy, remember?
这里有别人杀他了吗
Anyone else here kill that guy?
没有
Nope.
我猜也是
Didn't think so.
寇格  你跟大家说说
Korg, why don't you, uh, tell everybody
是谁砍掉了灭霸的大脑袋
who chopped Thanos' big head off?
风暴斧吗
Stormbreaker?
那是谁挥的风暴斧
Who was swinging Stormbreaker?
我懂的  你心里很难过
I get it. You're in a rough spot, okay?
我也经历过
I've been there myself.
知道是谁帮我走出来的吗
And you want to know who helped me out of it?
是娜塔莎吗
Was it Natasha?
是你
It was you.
是你帮了我
You helped me.
那你怎么不去问问
So, why don't you ask...
下面的阿斯加德人
the Asgardians down there...
我的帮助有多少价值
how much my help is worth?
至少是还剩下的那些
The ones that are left, anyway.
我觉得我们能把他们找回来
I think we could bring them back.
住口
Stop.
别说了  好吗
Stop, okay?
我知道你觉得我是待在这里
I know you think I'm down here
沉湎于自怨自艾之中
wallowing in my own self-pity...
等着有人来拯救
waiting to be rescued and saved...
但我没事  好吗  我们都没事  是吧
but I'm fine, okay. We're fine, aren't we?
我们很好  伙计
Oh, we're good here, mate.
所以  不管你有什么提议  我们不感兴趣
So, whatever it is that you're offering, we're not into it.
不在乎  完全不在乎
Don't care. Couldn't care less.
再见
Goodbye.
我们需要你  伙计
We need you, pal.
船上有啤酒
There's beer on the ship.
哪种的
What kind?
东京
是他  他来杀昭彦了
你为什么要这么做
我们跟你无冤无仇
你们还活着
半个地球的人却死了
他们因灭霸而死
你会死在我手里
你再别想伤害谁了
我们伤害人
你真是疯了
等等  救我
你想要什么我都给你
你想要什么
我想要的
What I want
你给不了
you can't give me.
你不该来的
You shouldn't be here.
你也不该
Neither should you.
我有工作要做
I've got a job to do.
你管这叫工作吗
Is that what you're calling this?
杀这些人也不能让你的家人回来
Killing all these people isn't gonna bring your family back.
我们有发现
We found something.
或许是一线希望
A chance, maybe.
别
Don't.
别什么
Don't what?
别给我希望
Don't give me hope.
很抱歉我没能早点给你
I'm sorry I couldn't give it to you sooner.
你左偏了
You're drifting left.
小心点  督爷
One side there, Lebowski.
火贱  干得怎么样了
Ratchet, how's it going?
是火箭
It's Rocket.
你放尊敬点  你只在地球上是天才  伙计
Take it easy. You're only a genius on Earth, pal.
时间旅行服  不赖啊
Time travel suit, not bad.
小心点
Easy! Easy!
我很小心了
I'm being very careful.
不  你很绿巨人
No, you're being very Hulky.
我很小心了
I'm being careful.
这可是皮姆粒子
These are Pym Particles, all right?
因为汉克·皮姆已被响指打消失了
And ever since Hank Pym got snapped out of existence,
我们只剩这些了
this is it.
我们只有这么多  我们再造不出更多了
This is what we have. We're not making any more.
-斯科特  冷静  -抱歉
- Scott, calm down. - Sorry.
我们只够每人往返一次  再就没了
We've got enough for one round-trip each. That's it.
不能重来
No do-overs.
还能做两次测试
Plus two test runs.
一次测试
One test run.
好吧  我没准备好呢
All right. I'm not ready for this.
我愿意
I'm game.
我去吧
I'll do it.
克林特  你会因时移
Clint, now you're gonna feel a little
而感到有些混乱
discombobulated from the chronoshift.
不用担心的
Don't worry about that.
等等  我问你件事
Wait, wait, wait a second. Let me ask you something.
如果我们能做到
If we can do this, you know...
回到过去  何不去找到婴儿灭霸
go back in time, why don't we just find baby Thanos?
然后...
You know, and...
首先  这太黑暗了
First of all, that's horrible.
那是灭霸啊
It's Thanos.
其次  时间不是那样的
And secondly, time doesn't work that way.
改变过去不能改变未来
Changing the past doesn't change the future.
我们回到过去  赶在灭霸之前
Look, we go back, we get the stones
拿到宝石
before Thanos gets them...
灭霸就拿不到宝石了  问题解决
Thanos doesn't have the stones. Problem solved.
-是啊  -原理不是这样的
- Bingo. - That's not how it works.
我听说是这样的
Well, that's what I heard.
谁  谁说的
Wait, but who? Who told you that?
《星际迷航》《终结者》《时间警察》
Star Trek, Terminator, Timecop...
-《两世奇人》  -《量子跳跃》
- Time After Time. - Quantum Leap.
《时间的皱折》《时光倒流七十年》
Wrinkle in Time, Somewhere in Time.
《热浴盆时光机》
Hot Tub Time Machine.
《比尔和泰德历险记》
Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure.
基本上所有讲时间旅行的电影都是这样的
Basically, any movie that deals with time travel.
《虎胆龙威》  不对  那个不是
Die Hard. No, that's not one.
这是已知定律
This is known.
我不知道为什么大家都相信那个
I don't know why everyone believes that,
但那不是真的
but that isn't true.
想想看  如果你回到过去
Think about it. If you travel to the past...
那过去就是你的未来了
that past becomes your future...
你之前的现在  就成了过去
and your former present becomes the past...
它是不能被你的新未来改变的
which can't now be changed by your new future.
没错
Exactly.
所以《回到未来》就是胡扯吗
So Back to the Future is a bunch of bullshit?
好  克林特
All right, Clint.
准备  三  二
We're going in three, two...
一
one.
库珀
Cooper?
-我的耳机呢  -莱拉
- Where are my headphones? - Lila?
-我没拿  -莱拉
- I never had them. - Lila?
你昨天拿了
Yeah, you had them yesterday!
莱拉  莱拉
Lila! Lila!
怎么了  爸爸
Yeah, Dad?
爸爸
Dad?
莱拉
Lila!
看着我
Look at me.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
成功了
It worked.
时间盗窃行动  加载头脑风暴会议
空间宝石
好  办法可行
Okay, so the how works.
力量宝石
现实宝石
现在我们得确定时间和地点
Now, we gotta figure out the when and the where.
时间宝石
灵魂宝石
这房间里几乎每个人都曾遭遇过
Almost everyone in this room has had an encounter
六颗无限宝石中的至少一颗
with at least one of the six Infinity Stones.
也可以把"遭遇"
Or substitute the word "encounter"
换成"差点被六颗
for "damn near been killed"
无限宝石中的一颗害死"
by one of the six Infinity Stones.
我没有
Well, I haven't...
但我根本不知道你们在说什么
but I don't even know what the hell you're all talking about.
不管怎样
Regardless,
我们剩的皮姆粒子
we only have enough Pym Particles
只够每人往返一次
for one round-trip each.
而这些宝石曾在
And these stones have been
历史上很多不同的地方出现过
in a lot of different places throughout history.
我们的历史
Our history.
所以  我们刚好能去的地方不多  是吧
So, not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in, yeah?
所以我们得选好目标
Which means we have to pick our targets.
没错
Correct.
那么
So,
先从以太粒子说起
let's start with the Aether.
托尔  你知道些什么
Thor, what do you know?
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
不不
No, no.
我肯定他是死了
I'm pretty sure he's dead.
现实宝石
从何说起呢
Where to start?
以太粒子  首先  它不是宝石
The Aether, firstly, is not a stone.
之前有人把它称为宝石
Someone called it a stone before.
它更像是团愤怒的烂泥
It's more of an angry sludge sort of a thing, so
得有人纠正一下
someone's gonna need to amend that
别再那么喊它了
and stop saying that.
关于以太粒子  有个有趣的故事
Here's an interesting story, though, about the Aether.
我祖父  很多年前
My grandfather, many years ago...
不得不把宝石藏在了黑暗精灵找不到的地方
had to hide the stone from the Dark Elves.
他们可吓人了
Scary beings.
简呢  其实
So, Jane, actually...
简·福斯特
她在这儿呢
There she is.
是啊  简是我的老情人
Yeah, so Jane was an old flame of mine.
她有次把手伸进了一块石头里
You know, she stuck her hand inside a rock this one time...
以太粒子就进入了她体内
and then the Aether stuck itself inside her...
她就病得很重
and she became very, very sick.
我不得不把她带回阿斯加德
And so I had to take her to Asgard,
我的家乡
which is where I'm from...
我们只能想办法治好她
and we had to try and fix her.
我们当时在约会
We were dating at the time, you see...
我还把她介绍给了我妈妈
and I got to introduce her to my mother...
她死了
who's dead and, um...
然后简和我也分手了
Oh, you know, Jane and I aren't even dating anymore, so...
这种事难免嘛
Yes, these things happen, though. You know?
没什么能天长地久  唯一...
Nothing lasts forever. The only thing that...
-你过来坐下吧  -我没说完呢
- Why don't you come sit down? - I'm not done yet.
人生中唯一永久不变的
The only thing that is permanent in life
就是它的无常
is impermanence.
说得太好了  鸡蛋  吃早饭吗
Awesome. Eggs? Breakfast?
不了  我想喝杯血腥玛丽
No. I'd like a Bloody Mary.
奎尔说他是在莫拉格偷走了力量宝石
Quill said he stole the Power Stone from Morag.
力量宝石
-那是个人吗  -不  莫拉格是个星球
- Is that a person? - No, Morag's a planet.
奎尔才是人
Quill was a person.
星球  是在外太空吗
Like a planet? Like in outer space?
看啊
Oh, look.
它就像只小狗  乐哈哈的
It's like a little puppy, all happy and everything.
你想去太空吗  想去吗  狗狗
Do you wanna go to space? You wanna go to space, puppy?
我可以带你去
I'll take you to space.
灵魂宝石
灭霸在沃密尔星球上找到了灵魂宝石
Thanos found the Soul Stone on Vormir.
沃密尔星球是什么
What is Vormir?
死亡之域
A dominion of death...
天体存在的中心
at the very center of celestial existence.
灭霸就在那里杀了我姐姐
It's where Thanos murdered my sister.
不去
Not it.
-那个时间宝石的家伙  -斯特兰奇博士
- That Time Stone guy. - Doctor Strange.
时间宝石
他是什么博士[医生]来着
Yeah, what kind of doctor was he?
耳鼻喉加帽子里抓兔子
Ear-nose-throat meets rabbit-from-hat.
他在格林威治有栋好房子
Nice place in the Village, though.
对  是在苏利文街吗
Yeah, on Sullivan Street?
-是布里克街  -等等  他住在纽约吗
- Bleecker Street. - Wait, he lived in New York?
-不  他住在多伦多  -对  布里克街
- No, he lived in Toronto. - Yeah, on Bleecker
-和苏利文街  -你好没好好听啊
- and Sullivan. - Have you been listening to anything?
伙计们
Guys.
如果选对了年
If you pick the right year,
能在纽约找到三枚宝石
there are three stones in New York.
不是吧
Shut the front door.
时间盗窃
纽约
空间宝石  心灵宝石  时间宝石
阿斯加德
现实宝石
莫格拉/沃密尔星球
力量宝石  灵魂宝石
好  我们有计划了
All right. We have a plan.
六颗宝石
Six stones,
三支队伍
three teams,
一次机会
one shot.
五年前  我们输了
Five years ago, we lost.
我们都输了
All of us.
我们失去了朋友
We lost friends.
我们失去了家人
We lost family.
我们失去了一部分自我
We lost a part of ourselves.
今天  我们有机会夺回那一切
Today, we have a chance to take it all back.
你们知道你们的分组
You know your teams.
也清楚你们的任务
You know your missions.
拿回宝石
Get the stones.
夺回一切
Get them back.
每人往返一次
One round-trip each.
不能犯错
No mistakes...
不能重来
no do-overs.
我们大部分人是要去熟悉的地方
Most of us are going somewhere we know.
但那不代表我们知道会遭遇什么
That doesn't mean we should know what to expect.
要小心
Be careful.
彼此照应
Look out for each other.
这是今生最重要的一战
This is the fight of our lives...
我们会赢的
and we're gonna win.
不惜一切
Whatever it takes.
大家好运
Good luck.
他真擅长这个
He's pretty good at that.
-是吧  -好了
- Right? - All right.
大家听到了
You heard the man.
按键盘吧  绿色快递
Stroke those keys, Jolly Green.
追踪器启动
Trackers engaged.
你保证把它完好地带回来吧
You promise to bring that back in one piece, right?
知道啦
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
好  我尽量
Okay, I'll do my best.
作为保证  这可不怎么样
As promises go, that was pretty lame.
一分钟后见
See ya in a minute.
纽  约
好了  我们各有各的任务
All right, we all have our assignments.
两颗宝石在上城区  一颗在下城区
Two stones uptown, one stone down.
低调点  注意时间
Stay low. Keep an eye on the clock.
随手砸点东西吧
Maybe smash a few things along the way.
我觉得没必要  但随便了
I think it's gratuitous, but whatever.
往那边走可要小心脚下
I'd be careful going that way.
我们刚给地板打了蜡
We just had the floors waxed.
我找斯特兰奇博士
Yeah, I'm looking for Doctor Strange.
你来早了大概五年
You're about five years too early.
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇现在正在那边大概
Stephen Strange is currently performing surgery
20个街区处做手术呢
about 20 blocks that way.
你找他要干什么
What do you want from him?
要那个
That, actually.
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
抱歉  但这不是请求
Sorry, but I wasn't asking.
你不想这么做的
You don't want to do this.
我是不想  但我需要那颗宝石
You're right, I don't. But I need that stone...
我没时间跟你争了
and I don't have time to debate it.
我们重新开始吧
Let's start over, shall we?
阿斯加德
给您的  简女士
For you, Lady Jane.
你们有...裤装吗
Do you have anything with pants?
裤装
Pants?
算了  这个就行  谢谢
Never mind. These will be fine. Thank you.
-是  女士  -简在那儿
- Yes, milady. - Oh, there's Jane.
好了
All right.
听好了  胖胖
Here's the deal, tubby.
你来迷倒她
You're gonna charm her,
我拿这个戳倒她
and I'm gonna poke her with this thing
抽走现实宝石  然后就麻溜走人
and extract the Reality Stone, and get gone lickety-split.
我马上回来  好吗
I'll be right back, okay?
酒窖就在这边
The wine cellar is just down here.
我父亲以前藏了几大桶的俄科尼麦芽酒
My father used to have this huge barrel of Aakonian ale.
我去碗碟室看看有没有外带杯
I'll see if the scullery has a couple of to-go cups.
你不是已经喝醉了吗
Aren't you drunk enough already?
麻烦你给洛基送点汤过去
If you could send Loki some soup.
是  陛下
Yes, milady.
叫我们的图书管理员
And ask our librarians
去天文区拿几卷书来
to pull some volumes from the astronomy shelf.
那个贵气的女人是谁
Who's the fancy broad?
我妈妈
That's my mother.
她今天会死
She dies today.
是今天吗
That is today?
我做不到
I can't do this. I can't do this.
我不该来的
I shouldn't be here. I shouldn't have come.
这是个坏主意
It's a bad idea!
-过来  -不不
- Come here. - No, no, no.
我觉得我恐慌发作了
I think I'm having a panic attack.
-过来  -我不该来的
- Come here. - I shouldn't be here.
-这里  -这不妙
- Right here. - This is bad.
你以为只有你失去了人吗
You think you're the only one who lost people?
你以为我们在干什么
What do you think we're doing here?
我失去了我唯一曾拥有过的家庭
I lost the only family I ever had.
奎尔  格鲁特  德拉克斯  触角妹
Quill, Groot, Drax, the chick with the antenna...
都没了
all gone.
我理解你想你妈妈
I get you miss your mom...
但她死了
but she's gone.
真死了
Really gone.
但还有很多人只是不在了
And there are plenty of people who are only kind of gone...
你可以帮他们
and you can help them.
所以这个要求过分吗
So, is it too much to ask
把你胡子里的食物渣子掸掉
that you brush the crumbs out of your beard...
去哄那个漂亮妞
make schmoopy talk to Pretty Pants...
趁她不备  吸走无限宝石
and when she's not looking, suck out the Infinity Stone...
然后帮我找回家人
and help me get my family back?
好
Okay.
你哭了吗
Are you crying?
没有
No.
对
Yes.
我觉得我要不行了
I feel like I'm losing it.
振作起来
Get it together!
你可以的
You can do this.
好吗
All right?
我可以的
Yes, I can.
很好
Good.
我可以的
I can do this. I can do this.
我做不到
I can't do this.
好了  女人杀手  她现在就一个人
All right, heartbreaker, she's alone.
我们的机会来了
This is our shot.
托尔
Thor?
Thor!
莫格拉
好  降下来  小蓝
All right, bring it down, Blue.
对准那条线  没错  再往下
Right on that line. That's it. Down, down.
能快点的吗
Can we hurry it up?
各位  快点  我们赶时间呢
Guys, chop-chop. Come on. We're on the clock.
这么催真的很有帮助
All that is really helpful.
-要小心  好吗  -嗯
- Take care, okay? - Yeah.
拿到宝石就回来  别干别的
Get that stone and come back. No messing around.
我们行的
We got this.
-我们搞定这事吧  -好的
- Let's get it done. - Yes, sir.
回头见
I'll see you back.
你们彼此照应着点
You guys watch each other's six.
嗯
Yeah.
沃密尔星球的坐标已输入
Coordinates for Vormir are laid in.
他们只要不跌出来就行
All they have to do is not fall out.
我们离布达佩斯可很远了
We're a long way from Budapest.
好吧
Okay, so, uh...
我们就等着这个奎尔出现
we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
然后他就会带我们找到力量宝石  是吗
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我们找掩护吧
Let's take cover.
2014年时  我们不是唯一在找宝石的人
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
等等  你在说什么呢
Wait a minute. What are you talking about right now?
还有谁在找宝石
Who else is looking for these stones?
我父亲
My father...
我姐姐
my sister...
和我
and me.
还有你
And you?
你现在在哪
Where are you right now?
不客气
You're welcome.
我没叫你帮忙
I didn't ask for your help.
但你总需要我帮
And yet, you always need it.
起来  父亲要我们回飞船上
Get up. Father wants us back on the ship.
为什么
Why?
他找到了一颗无限宝石
He's found an Infinity Stone.
在哪
Where?
在一颗叫莫格拉的星球上
On a planet called Morag.
父亲的计划总算开始运作了
Father's plan is finally in motion.
一颗宝石可不比六颗  星云
One stone isn't six, Nebula.
这是个开始
It's a start.
如果他能拿到全部...
If he gets all of them...
罗南已找到了力量宝石
Ronan's located the Power Stone.
我要派你们去他的飞船上
I'm dispatching you to his ship.
他不会高兴的
He won't like that.
他不配合就得死
His alternative is death.
罗南的执迷
Ronan's obsession...
影响了他的判断力
clouds his judgment.
我们不会让你失望的  父亲
We will not fail you, Father.
是啊  你不会的
No, you won't.
我发誓
I swear...
我会让你骄傲的
I will make you proud.
我们就等着这个奎尔出现
...we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
然后他就会带我们找到力量宝石  是吗
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我们找掩护吧
Let's take cover.
2014年时  我们不是唯一在找宝石的人
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
那是谁
Who was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我头痛欲裂  我不知道
My head is splitting. I don't know.
她的突触驱动可能在打斗中损伤了
Her synaptic drive was probably damaged in battle.
把她带上我的飞船
Bring her to my ship.
快点吧  队长
Better hustle, Cap.
这边看上去像是快要完事了
Things look like they're just about wrapped up here.
收到  我正在往电梯去
Got it. I'm approaching the elevator now.
如果你们不介意
If it's all the same to you...
我现在想来一杯
I'll have that drink now.
好  把他拉起来
All right, get him on his feet.
我们稍后再傻站着摆姿势吧
We can all stand around posing up a storm later.
对了  你们可以收拾一下
By the way, feel free to clean up.
罗杰斯先生  我差点忘了  那身战衣
Mr. Rogers, I almost forgot that that suit...
太不衬你的屁股了
did nothing for your ass.
你非得看吗  托尼
No one asked you to look, Tony.
真荒唐
It's ridiculous.
我觉得你很帅  队长
I think you look great, Cap.
在我看来  那就是美国屁股
As far as I'm concerned, that's America's ass.
魔杖归谁
Who gets the, uh, magic wand?
突击队正在赶来收走它
S.T.R.I.K.E. Team's coming to secure it.
那个交给我们吧
We can take that off your hands.
请吧
By all means.
小心哦
Careful with that thing.
是啊  除非你想被抹除思想
Yeah, unless you want your mind erased.
而且可不好玩
And not in a fun way.
我们一定小心
We promise to be careful.
他们是谁
Who are these guys?
他们是神盾局的
They are S.H.I.E.L.D.
但其实是九头蛇的  但我们当时不知道
Well, actually Hydra, but we didn't know that yet.
真的吗  你们不知道
Seriously? You didn't? I mean,
他们一看就不像好人啊
they look like bad guys.
你虽然个头小  但好聒噪
You're small, but you're talking loud.
这就下去协调搜救工作
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
真的  你怎么做到不吐的
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
闭嘴
Shut up.
好  该你上了  小伙计
All right, you're up, little buddy.
我们的宝石在那里呢
There's our stone.
好
All right.
弹我
Flick me.
让开
Move.
伙计
Buddy!
你怎么想的  已达到承载上限了
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
走楼梯吧
Take the stairs.
是啊  别别
Yeah. Stop, stop.
"走楼梯"  讨厌楼梯
"Take the stairs." Hate the stairs.
好了  队长  权杖在电梯里
All right, Cap, I got our scepter in the elevator...
刚过80层
just passing the 80th floor.
知道了
On it.
去大堂
Head to the lobby.
好  在那里碰头
All right, I'll see you there.
证据已收押
Evidence secure.
我们这就去找李斯特博士
We're en route to Doctor List.
不  毫无意外  部长先生
No. No hitches at all, Mr. Secretary.
队长
Captain.
我以为你去协调搜救行动了
I thought you were coordinating search and rescue.
计划有变
Change of plans.
队长
Hey, Cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
我刚接到了部长的电话
I just got a call from the secretary.
权杖的事将由我负责
I'm gonna be running point on the scepter.
长官  我不懂
Sir? I don't understand.
我们收到消息  可能有人会企图偷它
We got word there may be an attempt to steal it.
抱歉  队长
Sorry, Cap.
我们不能把权杖给你
We can't give you the scepter.
我得打给局长
I'm gonna have to call the director.
没事  相信我
That's okay. Trust me.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
好多楼梯啊
So many stairs!
拇指姑娘  收到吗  我看到目标了
Thumbelina, do you copy? I've got eyes on the prize.
可以开始了
It is go time.
炸吧
Bombs away.
那是AXE香氛吗
Is that Axe Body Spray?
对  我桌子里常备一罐应急的  放松啦
Yeah, I had a can in the desk for emergencies. Relax.
可以专心点吗
Can we focus, please?
我要进入你了
I'm going inside you...
行动
now.
可以问问你们要去哪吗
May I ask you where you're going?
吃点午饭  然后去阿斯加德
Bit of lunch and then Asgard.
抱歉  你是...
I'm sorry, you are...?
亚历山大·皮尔斯
Alexander Pierce.
他是尼克·弗瑞背后老大的老大
He's the man above the folks behind Nick Fury.
我的朋友喊我部长先生
My friends call me Mr. Secretary.
我得请你把那位犯人交给我
I'm gonna have to ask you to turn that prisoner over to me.
洛基会去向奥丁做个交待的
Loki will be answering to Odin himself.
不  他得向我们做交待
No, he's going to answer to us.
我们审过了再给奥丁
Odin can have what's left.
我还要拿走那个箱子
And I'm gonna need that case.
那七十多年来都是神盾局的财产
That's been S.H.I.E.L.D. property for over 70 years.
交出箱子  斯塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
好  行动吧  精灵鼠小弟
All right, move it, Stuart Little.
这边情况有点麻烦了  快点的
Things are getting dicey out here. Let's go.
我不打算争论这里谁的权力更高
I'm not gonna argue who's got the higher authority here...
你保证你不会死吗
You promise me you won't die?
我们只是要让我稍稍心律失常
We're only giving me a mild cardiac dysrhythmia.
那听上去很暴力啊
That doesn't sound mild.
我需要那个箱子
I need the case.
我知道你权力挺大的  我只是说
I know you got a lot of pull, I'm just saying,
-管辖权...  -好吧  那给我箱子
- jurisdiction... - Okay, then give me the case.
管辖权...
Well, jurisdiction...
交出来
Hand it over.
动手  朗
Do it, Lang!
手拿开
Get your hands off me.
快没时间了  拔线
Window's closing. Pull my pin.
来了
Here goes!
-斯塔克  -斯塔克
- Stark? - Stark?
他在抽搐  给他点空间
He's convulsing. Give him air!
-医务人员  -医务人员
- Medic! - Medic!
他们需要帮助
Give these guys some help.
说话啊
Speak to me.
斯塔克  是你的胸口机器吗
Stark, is it your chest machine?
呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
好样的  巷子里见
Good job. Meet me in the alley.
我去找点吃的
I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不走楼梯
No stairs!
拜托  斯塔克  保持清醒
Come on, Stark, stay with us.
我要试个办法  好吗
I'm going to try something. Okay?
我也不知道行不行
I have no idea if it's going to work.
好啊
Yes!
非常行啊
That worked a treat.
哥们  真疯狂
Dude, that was so crazy.
我完全不知道那行不行
I had no idea if that was gonna work.
-箱子呢  -箱子
- The case. - The case is, uh...
箱子呢  洛基呢
Where's the case? Where's Loki?
洛基
Loki!
那不符合计划  是吧
That wasn't supposed to happen, was it?
我们搞砸了
Oh, we blew it.
洛基
Loki?
托尼  怎么回事
Tony, what's going on?
告诉我你找到魔方了
Tell me you found that Cube.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be shitting me.
看到洛基了  14楼
I have eyes on Loki. 14th floor.
我不是洛基
I'm not Loki...
我也不想伤害你
and I don't wanna hurt you.
我可以和你耗一整天
I can do this all day.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
I know.
你从哪拿到的
Where did you get this?
巴基
Bucky
还
is
活着
alive.
什么
What?
确实是美国屁股
That is America's ass.
-拜托了  -对不起
- Please, please. - I'm sorry,
我帮不了你  布鲁斯
I can't help you, Bruce.
如果我交出时间宝石
If I give up the Time Stone
帮助你的现实  就是毁了我的现实
to help your reality, I'm dooming my own.
恕我直言
With all due respect, all right...
我觉得科学并不支持你这个说法
I'm not sure the science really supports that.
无限宝石
The Infinity Stones
创造了你所感知的时间流
create what you experience as the flow of time.
如果拿走一颗宝石
Remove one of the stones...
就会产生支流
and that flow splits.
这或许对你的现实有好处
Now, this may benefit your reality...
但对我新的这个  就不好了
but my new one, not so much.
在这个新的支流现实里
In this new branch reality...
没有了我们对抗
without our chief weapon
黑暗力量的首要武器
against the forces of darkness...
我们的世界会被颠覆
our world would be overrun.
数百万人会蒙受灾难
Millions will suffer.
告诉我  博士
So, tell me, Doctor.
你的科学能阻止这一切吗
Can your science prevent all that?
不能
No...
但我们可以抹除它
but we can erase it.
因为我们用完宝石后
Because once we're done with the stones...
我们可以把每一颗拿回原来的时间点
we can return each one to its own timeline...
放回被拿走的那一刻
at the moment it was taken.
这样  从时间上讲
So, chronologically...
在那个现实里
in that reality...
它就根本没被拿走过
it never left.
是啊  但你漏掉了最重要的部分
Yes, but you're leaving out the most important part.
要还回宝石  你们得能幸存下来
In order to return the stones, you have to survive.
我们会的  我会的  我保证
We will. I will. I promise.
我不能为了一句承诺拿这个现实冒险
I can't risk this reality on a promise.
至尊法师有责任
It's the duty of the Sorcerer Supreme
保护时间宝石
to protect the Time Stone.
那斯特兰奇为什么把它交了出去
Then why the hell did Strange give it away?
你说什么
What did you say?
斯特兰奇  他把宝石交给了灭霸
Strange. He gave it away. He gave it to Thanos.
-自愿的吗  -是的
- Willingly? - Yes.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I have no idea.
或许他错了
Maybe he made a mistake.
或是我错了
Or I did.
斯特兰奇将成为我们中最优秀的
Strange is meant to be the best of us.
所以他那么做肯定是有原因的
So, he must've done it for a reason.
你恐怕是对的
I fear you might be right.
谢谢
Thank you.
我指望你了  布鲁斯
I'm counting on you, Bruce.
我们都指望你了
We all are.
运行诊断
Run diagnostics.
给我看她的记忆文件
Show me her memory file.
大人  文件似乎凌乱了
Sire, the file appears entangled.
虽然有段记忆  但不属于她
It was a memory, but not hers.
还有另一个意识在与她共享网络
There's another consciousness sharing her network.
另一个星云
Another Nebula.
不可能
Impossible.
这个二重身有时间戳
This duplicate carries a time stamp...
是九年后的
from nine years in the future.
另一个星云在哪
Where is this other Nebula?
在我们太阳系里的莫格拉上
In our solar system on Morag.
你能读取她吗
Can you access her?
能  她俩是相连的
Yes, the two are linked.
搜索那个二重身的记忆
Search the duplicate's memories...
找无限宝石
for Infinity Stones.
而这些宝石曾在
And these stones have been
历史上很多不同的地方出现过
in a lot of different places throughout history.
我们的历史  所以
Our history. So,
我们刚好能去的地方不多  是吧
not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in, yeah?
所以我们得选好目标
Which means we have to pick our targets.
-没错  -定格
- Correct. - Freeze image.
地球人
Terrans.
复仇者
Avengers.
无法无天的讨厌鬼
Unruly wretches.
那个倒影是什么
What's that reflection?
放大它  乌木喉
Amplify this, Maw.
我不懂
I don't understand.
两个星云
Two Nebulas.
不  是一个星云
No. The same Nebula...
来自两个时间
from two different times.
设置航向去莫格拉
Set course for Morag.
并扫描那个二重身的记忆
And scan the duplicate's memories.
我想看到一切
I wanna see everything.
女士们  稍后见
My ladies, I'll see you after.
你们先去吧
I'll see you after. Go on ahead.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
天呐
Oh, God!
偷偷摸摸这种事最好还是交给你弟弟
You're better off leaving the sneaking to your brother.
我没偷偷摸摸  我就是出来走走
No, I wasn't sneaking. I was just going for a walk.
你穿的是什么啊
What are you wearing?
我总穿这件的  我最喜欢了
I always wear this. It's one of my favorites.
你的眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with your eye?
我的眼睛
Oh, my eye.
记得海拉根战役吗
Remember the, uh, Battle of Harokin...
我被大刀击中了脸
when I got hit in the face with the broadsword?
你根本不是我认识的托尔  是吧
You're not the Thor I know at all, are you?
我是的
Yes, I am.
看来未来对你很不好  是吧
The future hasn't been kind to you, has it?
我没说我是未来来的
I didn't say I was from the future.
我是被女巫养大的  孩子
I was raised by witches, boy.
我看东西不光靠眼睛  你知道的
I see with more than eyes, you know that.
是啊  我就是从未来来的
Yeah, I'm totally from the future.
是啊  亲爱的
Yes, you are, honey.
我真的需要跟你谈谈
I really need to talk to you.
我们可以谈谈
We can talk.
他的脑袋在这边
His head was over there...
他的身体在另一边
and his body over there...
有什么意义呢  我太迟了
I mean, what was the point? I was too late.
我就傻站在那里
I was just standing there.
一个拿着斧头的白痴
Some idiot with an axe.
你才不是白痴
Now, you're no idiot.
你不是来这儿了吗
You're here, aren't you?
向阿斯加德最睿智的人寻求建议
Seeking counsel from the wisest person in Asgard.
是啊
I am. Yes.
不是白痴
Idiot, no.
失败呢
A failure?
的确
Absolutely.
这有点残忍了吧
That's a little bit harsh.
知道那意味着你什么吗
Do you know what that makes you?
跟其他人一样
Just like everyone else.
我不是该与众不同的吗
I'm not supposed to be like everyone else, am I?
每个人都会辜负他人的期待  托尔
Everyone fails at who they're supposed to be, Thor.
衡量一个人  一个英雄的标准
The measure of a person, of a hero...
是他们能把真实的自己做得多好
is how well they succeed at being who they are.
我真的好想你  妈妈
I've really missed you, Mom.
托尔  我拿到了
Thor! I got it!
抓住那只兔子
Get that rabbit!
妈妈  我有事要告诉你
Mom, I have to tell you something.
不  儿子  你不用说
No, son, you don't.
你是来修复你的未来的  不是我的
You're here to repair your future, not mine.
-这就是关于你的未来  -那我管不着
- This is about your future.  - It's none of my business.
你就是妈妈吧
You must be Mom.
我拿到了  我们得走了
I got the thing. Come on. We gotta move.
真希望我们还有时间
I wish we had more time.
不  这已是恩赐
No, this was a gift.
你去做你该成为的那个人吧
Now you go and be the man you're meant to be.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, Mom.
我爱你
I love you.
吃点蔬菜吧
And eat a salad.
好了  我们得走了
Come on, we gotta go.
-再见  -三
- Goodbye. - Three...
-二  -不  等等
- Two... - No, wait!
什么情况啊
What am I looking at?
有时得需要点时间
Sometimes it takes a second.
我还有资格
I'm still worthy.
天呐
Oh, boy.
-再见  妈妈  -再见
- Goodbye, Mom. - Goodbye.
所以  他是个白痴吗
So, he's an idiot?
对
Yeah.
那是什么
What's that?
贼的工具
The tool of a thief.
按说这时候就会有尖刺冒出来
This is the part where you know, spikes come out...
上面还插着骷髅
with skeletons on the end of them and everything.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
当你闯入什么
When you break into a place called
"力量宝石神殿"时
"The Temple of the Power Stone"...
肯定会有一堆陷阱的
there's gonna be a bunch of booby traps.
-天呐  -好吧  行啊  你去吧
- Oh, my God. - Okay. All right. Go ahead.
我并不一直是如此的
I wasn't always like this.
我也一样
Me either.
但我们只能尽力而为了  是吧
But we work with what we got, right?
我们同步吧
Let's sync up.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
你杀了数万亿生灵
You murdered trillions!
你应该感激
You should be grateful.
宝石在哪
Where are the stones?
没了
Gone.
化成原子了
Reduced to atoms.
你两天前还用过的
You used them two days ago!
我用宝石摧毁了宝石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
差点要了我的命
It nearly killed me.
但大业已成
But the work is done.
注定会完成的
It always will be.
我是宿命
I am inevitable.
你对他们做了什么
What did you do to them?
没什么
Nothing.
还没做呢
Yet.
他们不是想阻止我要在
They're not trying to stop something
我们的时间里做的事
I'm going to do in our time.
他们是想撤销我已在
They're trying to undo something
他们的时间里做了的事
I've already done in theirs.
宝石
The stones.
我全拿到了
I found them all.
我赢了
I won.
让宇宙天平平衡了
Tipped the cosmic scales to balance.
这是你的未来
This is your future.
是我的命运
It's my destiny.
我父亲有很多特点
My father is many things.
但他不撒谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你  女儿
Thank you, daughter.
也许我过去对你太残酷了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
那就是实现了命运
And that is destiny fulfilled.
大人
Sire...
你女儿
your daughter...
不
No!
是个叛徒
...is a traitor.
那不是我  我绝不会的
That's not me. It's not, I could never...
我绝不会背叛你
I would never betray you.
绝不会
Never. Never.
我知道
I know.
你会有机会证明的
And you'll have the chance to prove it.
不
No!
他知道了
He knows!
巴顿  回复
Barton! Barton, come in.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff!
回复  我们有麻烦了
Come in, we have a problem.
拜托
Come on!
回复  我们...
Come in, we have a...
灭霸知道了
Thanos knows.
灭霸
Thanos...
队长
Cap.
抱歉  伙计  我们有麻烦了
Sorry, buddy, we got a problem.
是啊
Yeah, we do.
我们这下怎么办
Well, what are we gonna do now?
饶了我吧  史蒂夫
You know what? Give me a break, Steve.
我刚被绿巨人砸了脑袋
I just got hit in the head with the Hulk.
你说我们只有一次机会的
You said that we had one shot.
这就是我们的机会
This was our shot.
我们试了  没机会了
We shot it. It's shot.
六颗宝石  不然就不行
Six stones or nothing.
It was six stones or nothing.
你在重复自己的话  知道吗
You're repeating yourself, you know that?
你在重复自己的话
You're repeating yourself.
你才在重复自己的话
You're repeating yourself. You're repeating yourself.
-不  -哥们
- You know, no. - Dude.
-行了  -你当初就不想进行时间盗窃
- Come on! - You never wanted a time heist.
你不赞成时间盗窃
You weren't on board with the Time Heist.
-我搞砸了  -你毁了时间盗窃
- I dropped the ball. - You ruined the Time Heist.
-是吗  -是啊
- Is that what I did? - Yeah.
宇宙魔方还有其他选择吗
Are there any other options with the Tesseract?
没了  没有其他选择
No, no, no, there's no other options.
没法重来
There's no do-overs.
我们别想去别的地方了  我们只剩一剂粒子了
We're not going anywhere else. We have one particle left.
每人一剂
Each.
就这些了  好吗  我们用了
That's it. All right? We use that...
再见了  别想回家了
bye-bye, you're not going home.
如果我们不试试
Yeah, well, if we don't try...
那别人也都别想回家了
then no one else is going home, either.
我知道了
I got it.
还有别的办法能拿到宇宙魔方
There's another way to retake the Tesseract
并拿到更多粒子
and acquire new particles.
回忆一下
Little stroll down memory lane.
军队设施  花园之州
Military installation, Garden State.
它们什么时候同时都在
When were they both there?
它们都在...我大致知道是什么时候
They were there at a time... I have a vaguely exact idea.
-多大致  -你们在说什么
- How vague? - What are you talking about?
我们去哪
Where are we going?
-我确定它们在那里  -什么它们
- I know for a fact they were there. - Who's they?
-我们要干什么  -我也知道我怎么知道的
- What are we doing? - And I know how I know.
伙计们  怎么回事
Guys, what is it?
看来我们得即兴发挥了
Looks like we're improvising.
-好  -什么即兴发挥
- Great. - What are we improvising?
斯科特  把这个拿回基地
Scott, get this back to the compound.
准备
Suit up.
-新泽西有什么  -04
- What's in New Jersey? - 0-4.
0-4.
-07  -07
- 0-7. - 0-7.
-喂喂  -1970
- Excuse me. - 1-9-7-0.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
美队  队长
Cap? Captain?
史蒂夫  抱歉
Steve? Sorry.
美国  罗杰斯
America. Rogers.
如果你们去了
Look, if you do this...
但不成功  你们就回不来了
and it doesn't work, you're not coming back.
谢谢你的鼓励  小透明
Thanks for the pep talk, pissant.
你相信我吗
You trust me?
相信
I do.
你决定
Your call.
走吧
Here we go.
新泽西
不必多说
伙计  做爱  不作战
Hey, man! Make love, not war.
美国陆军里海军营  78步兵团
美国队长诞生地
你显然不是真在这里出生的吧
Clearly you weren't actually born here, right?
是我的概念的诞生地
The idea of me was.
好吧  如果你是神盾局
Right. Well, imagine you're S.H.I.E.L.D...
运作一个准法西斯情报机构
running a quasi-fascistic intelligence organization...
你会把它藏在哪
where do you hide it?
藏在眼皮下
In plain sight.
祝你任务顺利  队长
Good luck on your mission, Captain.
祝你项目顺利  博士
Good luck on your project, Doctor.
你新来的吗
You new here?
并不是
Not exactly.
快点
Come on, you bastard.
目标已找到
找到了
Gotcha.
又有戏了
Back in the game.
阿尼姆  是你吗
Arnim, you in there?
阿尼姆
Arnim?
门在这边  伙计
The door is this way, pal.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
找佐拉博士呢  看到他了吗
Looking for Doctor Zola, have you seen him?
嗯  佐拉博士  我谁都没看见
Yeah, Doctor Zola. No, I haven't seen a soul.
请原谅
Pardon me.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
不  先生
No, sir. I'm...
我是麻省理工学院来参观的
I'm a visitor from MIT.
麻省理工学院
MIT.
叫什么
Got a name?
霍华德
Howard.
-那我好记了  -霍华德
- That'll be easy to remember. - Howard...
波茨
Potts.
我是霍华德·斯塔克
Well, I'm Howard Stark.
握我  别拉
Shake that, don't pull it.
拉手指放屁
嗯
Yeah.
你脸色不太好啊  波茨
You look a little green around the gills, there, Potts.
我没事  就是干活儿累了
I'm fine. Just long hours.
想去呼吸下新鲜空气吗
You wanna get some air?
-喂  波茨  -好
- Hello, Potts. - Yeah.
-那太好了  -这边走
- That'd be swell. - That way.
好
Okay.
要拿上你的箱子吗
Need your briefcase?
你不是那种垮掉的一代吧  波茨
You're not one of those beatniks, are you, Potts?
-喂  -皮姆博士
- Hello? - Doctor Pym?
你打的是这个号码  没错
That would be the number that you called, yes.
我是运输部的史蒂文斯上尉
This is Captain Stevens from shipping.
这里有个给你的包裹
We have a package for you.
拿上来吧
Bring it up.
问题就在这里  先生  我们没法拿
That's the thing, sir, we can't.
我不懂  那不是你的工作吗
I'm confused. I thought that was your job.
就是...
Well, it's just...
先生  这盒子在发光
Sir, the box is glowing...
老实说
and to be honest,
几个邮递员也不太舒服
some of our mail guys aren't feeling that great.
他们没打开它吧
They didn't open it, did they?
他们开了  您最好赶紧来
Yeah, they did. You better get down here.
借过  让开
Excuse me! Out of the way!
皮姆粒子  勿动
鲜花和德国泡菜  今晚有重要约会吗
So, flowers and sauerkraut. You got a big date tonight?
我妻子要生了
My wife's expecting.
平时我又老泡办公室
And too much time at the office.
恭喜
Congratulations.
-谢谢  替我拿下  -好
- Thanks. Hold this, will ya? - Yeah, sure.
-她怀多久了  -不知道
- How far along is she? - I don't know.
反正她现在
She's at the point
受不了我嚼东西的声音
where she can't stand the sound of my chewing.
看来我又得去餐具室吃晚饭了
I guess I'll be eating dinner in the pantry again.
我有个女儿
I have a little girl.
是女儿就好了
A girl would be nice.
那样她比较不太可能变成我这样
Less of a chance she'd turn out exactly like me.
那有什么不好的
What'd be so awful about that?
这么说吧  我很少能
Let's just say that the greater good
把大局放在自利之上
has rarely outweighed my own self-interest.
你从未见过这两人吗
And you've never seen these two men before?
没  我眼神很刁的  他俩看上去很可疑
No, I've got an eye for this. The two of them looked fishy.
可以描述一下吗
Can you describe them?
其中一个留了嬉皮士胡子
One of them had a hippie beard.
嬉皮士  是比吉斯乐队还是蒙格·杰里那种
Hippie. Like Bee Gees or Mungo Jerry?
绝对是蒙格·杰里
Definitely Mungo Jerry.
我是切斯特
Yeah, this is Chesler.
所有可调动宪兵前往地下六层
I need every available MP to sublevel six.
可能有人闯入
We have a potential breach.
玛格丽特·卡特局长
我说了叫他们回来
I said bring them in.
他们在试了  长官
They're trying, ma'am,
但布拉多克的小队被雷击阻拦了
but Braddock's unit has been stopped by lightning strikes.
老天爷啊
Oh, for the love of...
我会看看天气预报的
I'll look at the weather projections.
这可不是雷击
It's not lightning strikes we're looking at.
名字想得怎么样了
So, where you at with names?
如果是男孩  我妻子想叫埃蒙泽
Well, if it's a boy, my wife likes Elmonzo.
还是再考虑考虑吧  还有时间呢
Might wanna let that stew awhile. You got time.
我问问你
Let me ask you a question.
你孩子出生时
When your kid was born,
你紧张吗
were you nervous?
可紧张了
Wildly.
-是啊  -你觉得自己够格吗
- Yeah. - Did you feel qualified?
你知道
Like you had any idea
要怎么成功操作那玩意吗
how to successfully operate that thing?
我真的是一边干一边学的
I literally pieced it together as I went along.
我回想了我爸爸是怎么做的
I thought about what my dad did.
我老爸  他什么问题都用皮带解决
My old man, he never met a problem he couldn't solve with a belt.
我以前觉得我爸爸对我很严厉
I thought my dad was tough on me.
而如今回想起来
And now, looking back on it,
我只记得那些美好的回忆
I just remember the good stuff.
他偶尔也说过些金句
You know? He did drop the odd pearl.
是吗  比如呢
Yeah? Like what?
"千金难买寸光阴"
"No amount of money ever bought a second of time."
他很睿智
Smart guy.
他尽力了
He did his best.
我跟你说  那孩子还没出生
I'll tell you, that kid's not even here yet
我已经愿意为他付出一切了
and there's nothing I wouldn't do for him.
很高兴认识你  波茨
Good to meet you, Potts.
我也是
Yeah.
霍华德
Howard...
一切都会没事的
everything's gonna be all right.
谢谢你
Thank you...
做的一切
for everything...
为这个国家做的一切
you've done for this country.
贾维斯
Jarvis.
我们见过那个人吗
Have we ever met that guy?
您每天会见到很多人  先生
You meet a lot of people, sir.
看着很眼熟
Seems very familiar.
胡子挺怪的
Weird beard.
你好弱
You're weak.
我就是你
I'm you.
你可以阻止这一切
You could stop this.
你知道你想的
You know you want to.
你看到未来发生了什么吗
Did you see what happens in the future?
灭霸拿到了灵魂宝石
Thanos finds the Soul Stone.
你想知道他是怎么拿到的吗
You wanna know how he does that?
你想知道他对你做了什么吗
You wanna know what he does to you?
够了
That's enough.
你让我恶心
You disgust me.
但这不代表你毫无用处
But that doesn't mean you're useless.
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
沃密尔星球
要不是在这种情况下
Under different circumstances...
这本会很赞的
this would be totally awesome.
我敢说那浣熊不用爬山
I bet the raccoon didn't have to climb a mountain.
严格说  他也不是浣熊
Technically he's not a raccoon, you know?
随便  反正他吃垃圾
Whatever. He eats garbage.
欢迎
Welcome.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
伊凡之女
Daughter of Ivan.
克林特
Clint.
伊迪丝之子
Son of Edith.
你是谁
Who are you?
就当我是向导
Consider me a guide...
指引你们
to you...
和所有人寻找灵魂宝石的人
and to all who seek the Soul Stone.
很好
Oh, good.
你告诉我们宝石在哪  我们马上就去
You tell us where it is, then we'll be on our way.
亲爱的
Liebling.
要是那么简单就好了
If only it were that easy.
你所寻找的就在你面前
What you seek lies in front of you.
你所害怕的也在那里
As does what you fear.
宝石就在下面
The stone's down there.
只能给一个人
For one of you.
而另一个
For the other...
要得到灵魂宝石
In order to take the stone...
你必须失去自己的珍爱之物
you must lose that which you love.
永恒的交换
An everlasting exchange.
以一个灵魂  换一个灵魂
A soul for a soul.
你好啊
How's it going?
老天
Jesus.
这可能都是他编的
Maybe he's making this shit up.
不
No.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
为什么  就因为他知道你爸爸的名字吗
Why? 'Cause he knows your daddy's name?
连我都不知道
I didn't.
灭霸带着灵魂宝石离开了这里
Thanos left here with the stone...
却没带走他女儿
without his daughter.
那不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
的确
Yeah.
不惜一切
Whatever it takes.
如果我们拿不到宝石
If we don't get that stone...
几十亿人就不能复生
billions of people stay dead.
是啊
Yeah.
我想我们都知道该牺牲的是谁了
Then I guess we both know who it's gotta be.
我想是的
I guess we do.
我开始觉得
I'm starting to think
我们想的不是一个人  娜塔莎
we mean different people here, Natasha.
过去五年来  我一直在为一件事努力
For the last five years, I've been trying to do one thing.
就是此刻
Get to right here.
一切都是为了此刻  让所有人复生
That's all it's been about. Bringing everybody back.
不  你别在这时候跟我装伟大
No, don't you get all decent on me now.
怎么  你以为我想这么做吗
What, you think I wanna do it?
我是在救你的命  傻瓜
I'm trying to save your life, you idiot.
可我不想让你救  行吗
Yeah, well, I don't want you to. How's that?
娜塔莎  你知道我都做了什么
Natasha, you know what I've done.
你知道我已变成了什么样的人
You know what I've become.
我不会以一个人最糟糕的错误来评判他
I don't judge people on their worst mistakes.
或许你应该这样
Maybe you should.
你当年就没有
You didn't.
你真是太烦人了  你知道吗
You're a pain in my ass, you know that?
好
Okay.
你赢了
You win.
跟我家人说我爱他们
Tell my family I love 'em.
你自己告诉他们
You tell 'em yourself.
该死的
Damn you.
等等
Wait.
放手吧
Let me go.
不
No.
不要啊
No. Please, no.
没事的
It's okay.
别
Please.
不要
No!
我们都拿到了吗
Did we get 'em all?
你是说真成功了吗
Are you telling me this actually worked?
克林特  小娜呢
Clint, where's Nat?
她有家人吗
Do we know if she had family?
有
Yeah.
我们
Us.
什么
What?
-你干什么  -就是问他个问题
- What are you doing? - Just asked him a question.
不  你一副她已经死了的样子
Yeah, no, you're acting like she's dead.
我们为什么一副她已经死了的样子
Why are we acting like she's dead?
我们有宝石啊
We have the stones, right?
只要我们有宝石  队长
As long as we have the stones, Cap,
我们能复活她的  是吧
we can bring her back. Isn't that right?
别垂头丧气的了  我们是复仇者  振作起来
So, stop this shit. We're the Avengers. Get it together.
不能复活她
Can't get her back.
他说什么...什么
What's he...? What?
不能撤销
It can't be undone.
不能
It can't.
对不起  别介意
Look, I'm sorry, no offense, but
但你就是个地球人  好吗
you're a very earthly being, okay?
这可是太空魔法
And we're talking about space magic.
"不能"也太绝对了  不是吗
And "can't" seems very definitive. Don't you think?
我知道这远超我的水平
Yeah, look, I know that I'm way outside my pay grade here.
但她还是不在  是吧
But she still isn't here, is she?
我就是这意思
No, that's my point.
是不能撤销的
It can't be undone.
至少
Or that's at least
那个飘着的红人是这么说的
what the red, floating guy had to say.
或许你该去跟他谈谈
Maybe you wanna go talk to him, okay?
你去拿上锤子  飞过去  跟他谈谈
Go grab your hammer and you go fly and you talk to him.
本该是我的
It was supposed to be me.
她为了那颗宝石牺牲了生命
She sacrificed her life for that goddamn stone.
她赌上了性命
She bet her life on it.
她回不来了
She's not coming back.
我们不能让她白死
We have to make it worth it.
绝对不能
We have to.
不会的
We will.
好  手套准备好了
All right, the glove's ready.
问题是  谁来打指响
Question is, who's gonna snap their freakin' fingers?
我来
I'll do it.
-什么  -没事
- Excuse me? - It's okay.
-不不  -打住  别急
- No, no, no. - Stop, stop. Slow down.
托尔  等等
Thor. Just wait.
我们还没决定由谁来戴
We haven't decided who's gonna put that on yet.
不好意思  难道我们还要干坐着
I'm sorry. What, we're all just sitting around
等待合适时机吗
waiting for the right opportunity?
我们至少该谈谈
We should at least discuss it.
坐在这里盯着它看
Look, sitting here staring at the thing
是不会让大家复活的
is not gonna bring everybody back.
我是最强的复仇者  好吗
I'm the strongest Avenger, okay?
所以这责任该由我来担
So, this responsibility falls upon me.
-一般来说  你是对的  -这是我的责任
- Normally, you're right. - It's my duty.
-但那不是重点  -不是那个
- It's not about that. - It's not that.
-伙计  -住口  让我来吧
- Hey, buddy... - Stop it! Just let me.
让我来吧
Just let me do it.
让我做件好事  做件对的事
Just let me do something good. Something right.
这不光是因为
Look, it's not just the fact that
那只手套所承载的能量
that glove is channeling enough energy
足以点亮一个大陆
to light up a continent.
相信我  你的状态不行
I'm telling you. You're in no condition.
你以为我现在血管里流的是什么
What do you think is coursing through my veins right now?
奶酪吗
Cheez Whiz?
雷电
Lightning.
-是啊  -雷电
- Yeah. - Lightning.
雷电也帮不了你  伙计
Lightning won't help you, pal.
得由我来
It's gotta be me.
你们看到宝石对灭霸的伤害了
You saw what those stones did to Thanos.
他差点没命
They almost killed him.
你们都撑不住的
None of you could survive.
我们怎么知道你撑得住
How do we know you will?
我们不知道
We don't.
但辐射主要就是伽马射线
But the radiation's mostly gamma.
就好像
It's like...
我是为此而诞生的
I was made for this.
可以了吗
Good to go, yeah?
开始吧
Let's do it.
好  记住
Okay, remember,
五年前被灭霸的指响打没的人
everyone Thanos snapped away five years ago
你把他们带回来  回到现在  今天来
you're just bringing them back to now, today.
别改变过去五年里的任何事
Don't change anything from the last five years.
好的
Got it.
星期五  帮个忙
Friday, do me a favor
启动谷仓门协议  好吗
and activate Barn Door Protocol, will ya?
是  老板
Yes, boss.
大家回家吧
Everybody comes home.
摘掉
Take it off! Take it off!
不  等等  布鲁斯  你没事吧
No, wait. Bruce, are you okay?
说话  班纳
Talk to me, Banner.
我没事
I'm okay.
传送门开启  源点2014年
布鲁斯
Bruce!
别碰他
Don't move him.
-成功了吗  -我们不确定  没事的
- Did it work? - We're not sure. It's okay.
劳拉
亲爱的
Honey.
克林特
Clint?
亲爱的
Honey.
各位
Guys...
好像成功了
I think it worked.
我无法呼吸了
I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
脱罩
Canopy, canopy, canopy.
罗德  火箭  快出去
Rhodey, Rocket, get out of here.
放我出去
Let me up! Let me up!
快点
Come on!
罗德
Rhodey!
求救  有人收到吗
Mayday, Mayday! Does anybody copy?
我们在下层  淹水了
We're on the lower level. It's flooding!
什么
What? What?
我们要淹死了  有人收到吗  求救
We are drowning! Does anybody copy? Mayday!
等等  我在
Wait! I'm here!
我在  收到了吗
I'm here. Can you hear me?
队长
Cap?
好吧
Okay.
女儿
Daughter.
是  父亲
Yes, Father.
这就是未来
So, this is the future.
好样的
Well done.
谢谢  父亲
Thank you, Father.
他们毫未怀疑
They suspected nothing.
自大者总是如此
The arrogant never do.
去
Go.
找到宝石  拿给我
Find the stones, bring them to me.
你要做什么
What will you do?
等着
Wait.
告诉我
Tell me something.
在未来
In the future...
你和我怎么样了
what happens to you and me?
我企图杀你
I try to kill you.
好几次
Several times.
但最终
But eventually...
我们成了朋友
we become friends.
我们成了姐妹
We become sisters.
来吧
Come on.
我们可以阻止他
We can stop him.
拜托  伙计  醒醒
Come on, buddy, wake up!
这就对了
That's my man.
你再弄丢  我可就不还你了
You lose this again, I'm keeping it.
怎么回事
What happened?
你扰乱时间  时间就给你捣乱
You mess with time, it tends to mess back.
你会明白的
You'll see.
他都干什么了
What's he been doing?
什么都没干
Absolutely nothing.
宝石呢
Where are the stones?
在这堆东西下面
Somewhere under all this.
我只知道他没拿到
All I know is he doesn't have 'em.
那就别让他拿到
So, we keep it that way.
你们知道这是陷阱吧
You know it's a trap, right?
知道
Yeah.
我不怎么在乎
I don't much care.
很好
Good.
只要我们都达成一致就行
Just as long as we're all in agreement.
我们这次要好好杀了他
Let's kill him properly this time.
你们无法承受自己的失败
You could not live with your own failure.
结果如何呢
Where did that bring you?
又跟我碰面了
Back to me.
我本以为抹除了一半的生命
I thought by eliminating half of life...
另一半就能兴旺
the other half would thrive.
但你们让我知道
But you've shown me...
那是不可能的
that's impossible.
只要还有人记得曾经
And as long as there are those that remember what was...
就总会有人
there will always be those
无法接受可能的未来
that are unable to accept what can be.
他们会抵抗
They will resist.
对  我们就那么固执
Yep, we're all kinds of stubborn.
我很感激
I'm thankful.
因为现在
Because now...
我知道我该怎么办了
I know what I must do.
我要粉碎全宇宙  化为原子
I will shred this universe down to its last atom.
然后
And then...
再用你们替我收集的宝石
with the stones you've collected for me...
创造个新宇宙
create a new one...
充满生机
teeming with life...
它不会知道自己失去了什么
that knows not what it has lost...
只知道它被赋予了什么
but only what it has been given.
一个感恩的宇宙
A grateful universe.
从鲜血中诞生
Born out of blood.
他们不会知道的
They'll never know it.
因为你们活不到那时告诉他们
Because you won't be alive to tell them.
另一边见了  伙计
See you on the other side, man.
撑着  我来了
Hang on! I'm coming!
好啊
Yeah!
我认识你
I know you.
父亲
Father...
我拿到宝石了
I have the stones.
什么
What?
住手
Stop.
你要背叛我们
You're betraying us?
你不用这么做的
You don't have to do this.
我就是这样
I am this.
不  你不是
No, you're not.
你看到我们变成什么样了
You've seen what we become.
星云  听她的
Nebula, listen to her.
你可以改变的
You can change.
他不会允许的
He won't let me.
不要
No!
好  托尔  来吧
Okay, Thor. Hit me.
老板  醒醒
Boss, wake up!
我就知道
I knew it!
我南征北战这么多年
In all my years of conquest...
暴力
violence...
屠戮
slaughter...
从来不是出于私怨
it was never personal.
但告诉你们
But I'll tell you now...
我马上要对你们顽固讨厌的
what I'm about to do to your stubborn,
小星球做的事
annoying little planet...
我会非常
I'm gonna enjoy it...
享受其中的
very, very much.
队长  收到吗
Hey, Cap, you read me?
队长  我是山姆  收到吗
Cap, it's Sam. Can you hear me?
在你左边
On your left.
就这些人了吗
Is that everyone?
什么  你还嫌不够吗
What? You wanted more?
复仇者
Avengers...
集结
assemble.
死吧
Die!
不  那个给我
No, no, give me that.
你拿那个小的
You have the little one.
我去
Holy cow!
你不会相信都发生了什么的
You will not believe what's been going on.
还记得我们在太空里时吗
Do you remember when we were in space?
我化成灰了
And I got all dusty?
我肯定是昏了过去
And I must've passed out,
因为我醒来时  你不在了
because I woke up and you were gone.
但斯特兰奇博士在  他说
But Doctor Strange was there, right? And he was like...
"已经过去五年了  快走  他们需要我们"
"It's been five years. Come on, they need us."
然后他就开始画那个亮亮的黄圈
And then he started doing the yellow sparkly thing
-就他老做的那个  -是吗
- that he does all the time. - He did? Oh, no.
你干什么
What are you doing?
感觉好棒
Oh, this is nice.
卡魔拉
Gamora?
我以为我失去了你
I thought I lost you.
别  碰  我
Don't touch me!
你第一次没打中
You missed the first time.
然后第二次你一下踢中了俩
Then you got 'em both the second time.
就是他吗
This is the one?
不是吧
Seriously?
你只能在他和一棵树之间选择
Your choices were him or a tree.
队长
Cap!
你要我怎么处理这玩意啊
What do you want me to do with this damn thing?
把那些宝石拿得越远越好
Get those stones as far away as possible!
不
No!
我们还得把它们送回原处
We need to get 'em back where they came from.
没法送回去了
No way to get 'em back.
灭霸毁了量子隧道
Thanos destroyed the quantum tunnel.
等等
Hold on!
那不是唯一的时间机器
That wasn't our only time machine.
有人看到一辆丑爆了的棕色货车了吗
Anyone see an ugly brown van out there?
看到了
Yes!
但你不会喜欢它停车的地方的
But you're not gonna like where it's parked!
斯科特  你启动它需要多久
Scott, how long you need to get that thing working?
大概10分钟
Maybe 10 minutes.
去启动机器  我们把宝石送去给你
Get it started. We'll get the stones to you.
好的  队长
We're on it, Cap.
你说是一千四百万之一的概率能赢  是吧
You said one out of 14 million, we win, yeah?
就是这次吧
Tell me this is it.
如果我告诉你会发生什么
If I tell you what happens...
就不会发生了
it won't happen.
你最好是对的
You better be right.
后面好乱
It's a mess back here.
没反应
It's dead.
-什么  -没反应
- What? - It's dead.
我得热启动试试
I have to hot-wire it.
星云呢
Where's Nebula?
她没回应
She's not responding.
大人
Sire...
克林特
Clint!
给我
Give it to me.
你夺走了我的一切
You took everything from me.
我都不知道你是谁
I don't even know who you are.
你会知道的
You will.
交给我
I got it!
启动击杀功能
Activate Instant Kill.
全力轰炸
Rain fire!
但大人  我们的部队
But, sire, our troops!
照办
Just do it!
有人看到了吗
Is anyone else seeing this?
我行的
I got this!
I got this.
好吧  我不行了
Okay, I don't got this.
救命  谁救救我
Help, somebody help!
皇后区  看上面
Hey, Queens, heads up!
抓住  有我呢  孩子
Hang on. I got you, kid.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you...
老天爷啊
Oh, my God!
怎么回事
What the hell is this?
星期五  他们在冲什么开火
Friday, what are they firing at?
有什么刚进入了上层大气
Something just entered the upper atmosphere.
好样的
Oh, yeah!
丹弗斯  我们这里需要帮助
Danvers, we need an assist here.
我是彼得·帕克
I'm Peter Parker.
彼得·帕克
Hey, Peter Parker.
你有什么要给我吗
You got something for me?
我不知道你要怎么通过那一关
I don't know how you're gonna get it through all of that.
别担心
Don't worry.
她不是一个人
She's got help.
我是宿命
I am inevitable.
我
And I...
是
am...
钢铁侠
Iron Man.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
斯塔克先生  你能听到我吗
Mr. Stark. Can you hear me?
我是彼得
It's Peter.
我们赢了  斯塔克先生
We won, Mr. Stark.
我们赢了  你做到了  先生  你做到了
We won! You did it, sir, you did it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
托尼
Tony.
小派
Hey, Pep.
星期五
Friday?
生命机能情况危急
Life functions critical.
托尼
Tony?
看着我
Look at me.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
你可以休息了
You can rest now.
大家都想要一个快乐的结局  对吗
Everybody wants a happy ending, right?
但世事难料
But it doesn't always roll that way.
也许这次的结局会是快乐的
Maybe this time.
我希望你们回放这个的时候
I'm hoping if you play this back...
是在庆祝
it's in celebration.
我希望家人能够团圆  我希望我们能挽回
I hope families are reunited. I hope we get it back.
这个星球能够回归
And something like a normal version
还算正常的版本
of the planet has been restored.
如果真有这种东西的话
If there ever was such a thing.
天呐  世界真奇妙  宇宙真奇妙
God, what a world. Universe, now.
如果你十年前跟我说我们并不孤单
If you told me 10 years ago that we weren't alone...
而且还热闹到这种程度
let alone to this extent, I mean,
我倒不会觉得惊讶
I wouldn't have been surprised...
但谁能想到呢
but come on, who knew?
轮番登场的史诗般的
The epic forces of darkness and light
黑暗和光明势力
that have come into play.
不管是好是坏
And for better or worse...
这就是将伴随摩根
that's the reality Morgan's gonna
成长的现实
have to find a way to grow up in.
所以  我觉得最好录下一段问候
So, I thought I'd probably better record a little greeting,
以防我英年早逝了
in the case of an untimely death. On my part.
虽然死亡总是来得太早
Not that death at any time isn't untimely.
我们明天要尝试的时间旅行
This time travel thing that we're gonna try and pull off tomorrow
真的很难说我们能不能活下来
it's got me scratching my head about the survivability of it all.
就是这样
That's the thing.
但是  做英雄就是如此  不是吗
Then again, that's the hero gig, right?
结束也是旅程的一部分
Part of the journey is the end.
我在耍什么疯
What am I even tripping for?
一切都会
Everything is gonna work out
如愿以偿的
exactly the way it's supposed to.
我爱你三千
I love you 3,000.
托尼·斯塔克有心的证明
我希望有什么办法
You know, I wish there was a way
能让她知道
that I could let her know.
我们胜利了
That we won.
我们做到了
We did it.
她知道的
She knows.
他们俩都知道
They both do.
你好吗  小姑娘
How you doing, squirt?
我很好
Good.
好吗
You good?
好  你饿了吗
Good. You hungry?
你想吃什么
What do you want?
奶酪汉堡
Cheeseburgers.
你爸爸也喜欢奶酪汉堡
You know, your dad liked cheeseburgers.
好啊
Okay.
你想吃多少奶酪汉堡我都给你买
I'm gonna get you all the cheeseburgers you want.
好
Okay.
那么...
So...
你什么时候回来
when can we expect you back?
这事嘛...
About that...
托尔  你的人民需要一个王
Thor, your people need a king.
不  他们已经有王了
No, they already have one.
真好笑
That's funny.
你是认真的吗
Are you being serious?
我该成为真正的自己
It's time for me to be who I am rather than
而不是去实现他人的期待
who I'm supposed to be.
但你  你是一个领袖
But you, you're a leader.
那就是真实的你
That's who you are.
我会在这里做出很多改变的
You know, I'd make a lot of changes around here.
我就指望你了
I'm counting on it...
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
那你要做什么
What will you do?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
千年以来  我第一次
For the first time in a thousand years,
失去了目标
I have no path.
但我有便车可以搭
I do have a ride though.
动作快点  大毛球
Move it or lose it, hairbag.
正在搜索
你们在这里啊
Oh, here we are!
树  见到你真高兴
Tree, good to see you.
阿斯加德银河护卫队又重聚了
The Asgardians of the Galaxy back together again.
我们先去哪儿
Where to first?
提醒你一下  这还是我的飞船
Just so you know, this is my ship still.
我说了算
I'm in charge.
我知道  当然是你说了算
I know. I know. Of course you are.
当然了
Of course.
你说"当然了"  但你又碰地图了
See, you say, "of course," but then you touch the map.
这会让人觉得
It makes you think that
也许你并不明白是我说了算
maybe you didn't realize I was in charge.
-葵尔  这只是你的不安全感  -葵尔
- Quail, that's your own insecurities in there. - Quail?
我只是想帮忙和协助
Okay? I am merely trying to be of service and assisting.
是奎尔
Quill.
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
你们应该为领袖地位的荣耀一战较高下
You should fight one another for the honor of leadership.
这样公平
Sounds fair.
-没必要吧  -没必要
- It's not necessary, okay? - It's not.
我有爆能枪
I got some blasters,
除非你们想用刀
unless you guys wanna use knives.
好啊  请用刀吧
Oh, yes! Please, use knives.
用刀吧
Yeah. Knives.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
没必要的
Not necessary.
我们不该以刀相见
There shall be no knifing one another.
大家都知道谁说了算
Everybody knows who's in charge.
我
Me.
对吧
Right?
没错  是你
Yes, you.
当然
Of course!
Of course.
当然
记住
Remember...
你得把宝石还回它们被拿走的那一刻
you have to return the stones to the exact moment you got 'em
否则就会开启一堆讨厌的平行现实
or you're gonna open up a bunch of nasty alternative realities.
别担心  布鲁斯
Don't worry, Bruce.
阻断所有时间分支
Clip all the branches.
我试过的
You know, I tried.
我戴着铁臂和宝石时
When I had the gauntlet, the stones,
我努力想把她带回来了
I really tried to bring her back.
我很想她
I miss her, man.
我也是
Me too.
如果你想  我可以跟你一起去
You know, if you want, I could come with you.
你是个好人  山姆
You're a good man, Sam.
但这次我要一个人去
This one's on me, though.
别干傻事  等我回来
Don't do anything stupid till I get back.
我怎么会
How can I?
你把傻气都带走了
You're taking all the stupid with you.
我会想你的  兄弟
Gonna miss you, buddy.
我不会有事的  巴基
It's gonna be okay, Buck.
他要去多久
How long is this gonna take?
他需要多久都行  对我们来说只有五秒钟
For him, as long as he needs. For us, five seconds.
准备好了吗  队长
You ready, Cap?
那我们在这儿等你回来了
All right, we'll meet you back here, okay?
没问题
You bet.
开启量子
Going quantum.
三
Three...
二
two...
一
one.
回归倒计时  五
And returning in five...
四
four...
三
three,
二
two...
一
one.
他人呢
Where is he?
不知道  他错过了他的时间戳
I don't know. He blew right by his time stamp.
他应该回来了
He should be here.
把他带回来
Get him back.
-我在弄呢  -赶紧把他带回来
- I'm trying. - Get him the hell back.
-我说了我在弄呢  -山姆
- Hey, I said I'm trying. - Sam.
去吧
Go ahead.
队长
Cap?
山姆
Hi, Sam.
是出了差错  还是一切如愿
So, did something go wrong or did something go right?
我把宝石放回去后  我想着
Well, after I put the stones back, I thought...
要不
maybe...
我去试试托尼叫我去过的那种生活吧
I'll try some of that life Tony was telling me to get.
结果如何
How'd that work out for ya?
妙不可言
It was beautiful.
那就好  我替你高兴
Good. I'm happy for you.
真心的
Truly.
谢谢
Thank you.
只有一件事让我不爽
Only thing bumming me out
就是我不得不生活在一个
is the fact I have to live in a world
没有美国队长的世界里
without Captain America.
这倒提醒了我
That reminds me.
试试吧
Try it on.
感觉如何
How does it feel?
感觉是别人的
Like it's someone else's.
不是了
It isn't.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会全力以赴的
I'll do my best.
所以它是你的了
That's why it's yours.
要不要和我说说她
You wanna tell me about her?
不
No.
不  还是算了
No, I don't think I will.